Okay. Hello everyone.
好的。大家好。
Um, welcome back to the second class of, um, CS224N.
嗯，欢迎回到第二类，嗯，CS224N。
Okay, so right at the end of last time I was just showing you a little,
好的，所以就在上次结束的时候我只是向你展示了一点，
um, from this, um,
嗯，从这个，嗯，
IPython Notebook of things that you could do with word vectors
你能用word向量做的事情的IPython笔记本
but I kind of ran out of time a little for a bit.
但是我有点过时了。
So, I'll just spend a couple of more minutes first,
所以，我先花几分钟时间，
um, showing the end of  this.
嗯，显示结束。
I stuck this IPython Notebook up on the course page.
我把这个IPython Notebook放在了课程页面上。
So, under lecture one you can find a copy of it and you can download it.
因此，在第一讲课中，您可以找到它的副本，您可以下载它。
So, I both stuck up just an HTML version of it and a zip file.
所以，我只是粘贴了它的HTML版本和一个zip文件。
Like HTML file is only good to look at.
像HTML文件一样只有好看。
You can't do anything with it.
你无法做任何事情。
So, you wanna, if you wanna play with it by yourself, um,
所以，你想，如果你想自己玩，嗯，
download the zip file and get the IPython Notebook out of that.
下载zip文件并从中获取IPython Notebook。
Okay. So we were looking at
好的。所以我们在看
these Glove word vectors which I'll talk about a bit more today and so there were
这些Glove单词向量，我今天会谈到更多，所以有
these sort of basic results of similarity in this vector space work very nicely for,
这种向量空间中这些相似的基本结果非常适合，
um, discovering similar words and then going on from that,
嗯，发现类似的话，然后继续，
there was this idea that we'll spend some more time on today which was, um,
有这个想法，我们今天会花更多的时间，这是，嗯，
maybe this vector space is not only a similarity space where
也许这个向量空间不仅仅是一个相似空间
close together things have similar meaning but it actually captures meaning
事物紧密结合在一起具有相似的意义，但它实际上捕捉了意
in a considerably deeper and more profound way which is to say that there are
以更深刻和更深刻的方式，也就是说有
actually directions in the space that you can point which have a certain meaning.
实际上你可以指出具有一定意义的空间方向。
So, that if you are pointing in one direction it means this is more so the case,
所以，如果你指向一个方向，那就意味着情况更是如此，
if you are pointing in a different direction and the meaning space it might be this is
如果你指向一个不同的方向和意义空间，它可能就是这样
the capital of this country or
这个国家的首都或
all sorts of different meanings could be encoded in the space.
可以在空间中编码各种不同的含义。
And a way of testing that,
还有一种测试方法，
is to use these analogy, um, problems.
就是用这些类比，嗯，问题。
And I quickly showed this at the end but just to make sure if you're
我最后很快就展示了这一点，但只是为了确定你是不是
unguarded since it's sort of- it's sort of a clever thing right?
因为它有点无人防守 - 这是一种聪明的事情吗？
So, the idea is that we're going to start with a pair of words like king and man.
所以，我们的想法是，我们将从像王和人这样的词开始。
And so what we're gonna do is we're gonna say well,
所以我们要做的就是说得好，
there's a vector for king in the space and there's a vector for man in
在太空中有一个国王的矢量，并且有一个载人的载体
the space and but what we're gonna do is we're going to
空间，但我们要做的就是我们要去的地方
subtract as in just good old vector subtraction that you hopefully learned in your,
减去你希望在你的学习中得到的好的老矢量减法，
um, linear algebra class.
嗯，线性代数课。
We're gonna subtract the man vector from
我们要从中减去man vector
the king vector and the idea we have in our head then is if we do
如果我们这样做的话，国王的载体和我们头脑中的想法就是如此
that what will happen is we'll be left with the meaning of kingship without the manness.
将要发生的事情是，如果没有人性，我们将被置于王权的意义之中。
Um, and so then there's also a direct vector for a woman.
嗯，然后还有一个女人的直接矢量。
So, we can add the woman vector to that resulting vector and then we could say well,
所以，我们可以将女性向量添加到结果向量中，然后我们可以说，
in the vector, we end up at some point in the vector space and then we're gonna say well,
在向量中，我们最终在向量空间中的某个点，然后我们会说好，
what's the closest word that you're gonna find the here
你在这里找到的最接近的词是什么
and it's gonna print out the closest word and as we saw,
它会打印出最接近的单词，正如我们所见，
um, last time, um,
嗯，上次，嗯，
lo and behold if you do that,
瞧，如果你这样做，
um, you get the answer.
嗯，你得到了答案。
I'm saying you get,
我说你明白了
um, king, man, woman.
嗯，国王，男人，女人。
No? All right. [LAUGHTER].
没有？行。 [笑声]。
You gotta reverse king and man.
你要逆转国王和男人。
I have to reverse king and,
我必须逆转国王，
ah, sure, sure, sure. I'm sorry.
啊，当然，当然，确定。对不起。
Oops. Yeah, okay, I kinda do it well like man, king.
哎呀。是的，好吧，我有点喜欢男人，国王。
Ah, [LAUGHTER] Okay. Yeah, that's right.
啊，[大笑]好的。是啊，没错。
Sorry. Okay. Yeah, because it should be
抱歉。好的。是的，因为它应该是
man is to king as woman is to something sorry yeah.
男人是国王，因为女人是抱歉的事。
I was getting [LAUGHTER] my order of components wrong.
我得到[笑声]我的组件顺序错了。
Okay. Um, and, you know,
好的。嗯，你知道，
as I was sort of I guess I was showing some examples last time with
因为我有点想，我上次展示了一些例子
nationality words but I mean this in a way that is sort of surprising to shocking,
国籍词，但我的意思是这种方式令人震惊，
this actually works for all kinds of things that you can get meaning in this space.
这实际上适用于你可以在这个空间中获得意义的各种事物。
So, I can ask various kinds of analogies of sorts.
所以，我可以问各种各样的类比。
So I can say Australia is to beer as France is to-.
所以我可以说澳大利亚是啤酒，因为法国是 - 。
Wine.
葡萄酒。
Wine. You might think wine.
葡萄酒。你可能会想到葡萄酒。
What it gives back as champagne which seems a pretty good answer.
它作为香槟回馈的东西似乎是一个很好的答案。
[LAUGHTER] Um, I'll go with that.
[大笑]嗯，我会跟着那个。
Um, um, you can do more syntactic facts.
嗯，嗯，你可以做更多的句法事实。
So, I can say tall ta- tall is to tallest as long is to longest and it gets set.
所以，我可以说最高的是最高的，只要最长，它就会被设定。
Um, if I say good is to fantastic as bad is to terrible.
嗯，如果我说好话就是太棒了，坏就是可怕。
That it seems to get out that there's some kind of notion of
似乎有人认为存在某种概念
make more extreme direction and get this direction out.
做出更加极端的方向并将这个方向排除在外。
I skipped over one.
我跳过了一个。
A bomber is to Clinton as Reagan is to.
正如里根所做的那样，轰炸机就是克林顿。
You may or may not like the answer it gives for this one
你可能会也可能不会喜欢这个答案
as Obama is to- as Reagan is to Nixon.
正如奥巴马所做的那样 - 里根是尼克松。
Um, now one thing you might notice at
嗯，现在你可能会注意到一件事
this point and this is something I actually want to come back to at the end.
这一点，这是我实际上想要回到最后的东西。
Um, well, there's this problem because Clinton's ambiguous, right?
嗯，有这个问题，因为克林顿暧昧，对吗？
There's Bill or there's Hillary.
比尔还是那里的希拉里。
Um, and, um, I forget,
嗯，嗯，我忘了，
you know, so this data as I said is a few years old.
你知道吗，所以我说的数据已有几年了。
So, this data was done in 2014.
因此，这些数据是在2014年完成的。
So, in sort of in- it definitely doesn't
所以，在某种程度上它肯定没有
have Trump really in it as a politician, um, but, you know,
让特朗普作为政治家真的参与其中，嗯，但是，你知道，
it would have variously both Clintons but as sort of makes sense if probably um,
如果可能的话，它会有各种各样的Clintons但是有道理，
for a sort of proof for 2014 data,
对于2014年数据的一种证明，
um, that Bill Clinton dominated.
嗯，比尔克林顿占主导地位。
So, I think what we're getting, um,
所以，我想我们得到了什么，嗯，
out of this is that Clinton and Nixon are sort of similar of people in dangers,
除此之外，克林顿和尼克松有点类似于危险的人，
um, of being impeached.
嗯，被弹劾。
Um, and, uh, on both sides of the aisle had us thinking primarily of Bill Clinton.
嗯，而且，呃，在过道的两边让我们主要考虑比尔克林顿。
But, um, if this sort of brings up something that
但是，嗯，如果这种东西带来的东西
I'll come back to right at the end of, um,
我会在最后回来，嗯，
it sort of looks like we've got a sort of a problem here because we
看起来我们在这里遇到了一个问题，因为我们
just have this string literally Clinton and that, um,
只是克林顿这个字符串，那个，嗯，
string is any possible sense and meaning of the string Clinton and so minimally um,
字符串是克林顿字符串的任何可能的意义和含义，所以最低限度，
that we have Bill Clinton and Hillary Clinton that near.
我们有比尔克林顿和希拉里克林顿那附近。
Maybe you have some friends that are called Clinton as well, right,
也许你有一些叫做克林顿的朋友，对，
and they're all mixed together in this Clinton.
在克林顿，他们都混在了一起。
And so that seems kinda problematic and that's sort of been an issue
所以这似乎有点问题，这是一个问题
that's been discussed some for these word vectors and I'll come back to that.
对于这些单词向量已经讨论了一些，我会回过头来看看。
Um, another thing you can do is you can give
嗯，你可以做的另一件事是你可以给
a set of words and say which is the odd one out.
一组单词，并说出哪一个是奇怪的。
Maybe you used to do puzzles like that in middle school or something.
也许你曾经在中学或其他什么地做过那样的谜题。
Um, and so you can do that and it decides
嗯，所以你可以这样做，它决定
that cereal is the odd one out of that set. It seems okay.
谷物是那个谷物中奇怪的一个。好像没关系。
Um, and then one other thing I'll just show you is, so, um,
嗯，然后我要告诉你的另一件事是，所以，嗯，
it'll sort of be nice to look at these words that I've drawn
看看我画的这些单词真是太好了
them in some of the slide pictures.
他们在一些幻灯片图片。
So, this is saying to put together a PCA or
所以，这就是说将PCA或PCA放在一起
Principal Components Analysis, um, scatter plot.
主成分分析，嗯，散点图。
Um, so, I can do that and then I can say, "Um,
嗯，所以，我可以这样做，然后我可以说，“嗯，
give it a set of words and draw me these as a scatter plot" and um,
给它一套文字并把它作为散点图画给我“和嗯，
hopefully if I can just about fit it in,
希望如果我可以适应它，
um, here's my scatter plot.
嗯，这是我的散点图。
And it works pretty well, right?
它运作得很好，对吧？
I've got the wine, champagne,
我有葡萄酒，香槟，
beer up here then the coffee and tea.
啤酒在这里然后是咖啡和茶。
Um, here are the countries.
嗯，这是国家。
Here is the schools, college institute, universities.
这里是学校，大学学院，大学。
Um, the animals are down here.
嗯，动物都在这里。
Um, foodstuffs there.
嗯，食品在那里。
So, yeah, this sort of really does work with this two direction- dimensional display.
所以，是的，这种两种方向尺寸显示确实有效。
It basically shows you similarity.
它基本上显示了你的相似性
Now, um, there are, you know,
现在，嗯，有，你知道，
to some extent though you want to hold on to your wallet with these PCA displays.
在某种程度上，虽然你想用这些PCA显示器保持你的钱包。
So, it's as I've discussed before since you're
所以，就像我之前讨论过的那样
taking something that was 100-dimensional and we're just doing
采取100维的东西，我们正在做
this 2D projection that is capturing some of the major geometry of
这个2D投影正在捕捉一些主要的几何形状
the space but it just has to be losing a huge amount of the information.
空间，但它只是必须丢失大量的信息。
So, when things end up close together,
所以，当事情最终靠近时，
they might be really close together in the original space or
它们可能在原始空间中非常接近或者
they might just have been words that lost in
他们可能只是失去了的话
the 2D projection because they- there are other patterns that
2D投影因为它们 - 还有其他模式
were more dominant and were chosen as the first two principal components.
更具优势，被选为前两个主要组成部分。
So, you sort of don't wanna over trust
所以，你有点不想过分信任
these things and something if you like Infoviz you might think
这些东西，如果你喜欢Infoviz，你可能会想到
about is how there are other ways that I might be able to
关于我可能有其他方式
represent the distances in a way that was more accurate.
以更准确的方式表示距离。
Um, but anyway this is very simple to do and I'm just getting
嗯，但无论如何这很简单，我只是得到了
a PCA to reduce the dimensionality of the matrix and then,
PCA减少矩阵的维数然后，
um, transforming with it these word vectors and printing them.
嗯，用它转换这些单词向量并打印它们。
Um, it's mainly easy to do.
嗯，这很容易做到。
The bit that wasn't easy for me to do, um,
这对我来说不容易，嗯，
but if someone's got some clever Python um plotting tips I'd like one,
但如果有人有一些聪明的Python um绘图提示我会喜欢一个，
if someone wants to send me a message after class.
如果有人想在课后给我发消息
I would have thought there'd be some default way in which you could just
我原本以为会有一些默认的方式
label points in a scatter plot but I wasn't able to find one.
散点图中的标签点，但我找不到。
So, what I did, um,
那么，我做了什么，嗯，
was I'm just sort of plotting the texts and
我只是在策划文本和
I'm offsetting it a little bit from the points.
我从点上略微抵消了它。
Um, now that works kinda crappily
嗯，现在有点疯狂
because they just collide with each other as you can see.
因为你可以看到它们只是相互碰撞。
Um, so, it'd be better if there was a better way to do point labeling in Python plots.
嗯，如果有更好的方法在Python图中做点标记会更好。
So, if anyone knows the answer to that one you can send it to me.
所以，如果有人知道那个答案，你可以发给我。
Um, okay. So, that's that. Ah.
嗯，好的。那就是那个。啊。
And if you haven't used IPython Notebooks
如果您还没有使用过IPython笔记本电脑
before and don't want your computer to run really slowly,
之前并且不希望您的计算机运行得非常慢，
it's a good idea to halt
停下来是个好主意
your IPython Notebooks when you're not gonna be using them anymore,
当你不再使用它们时，你的IPython笔记本电脑，
um, especially if they're computing something.
嗯，特别是如果他们正在计算某些东西。
Um, okay. [NOISE] Um.
嗯，好的。 [NOISE]嗯。
[NOISE]
[噪声]
Okay. [NOISE] So now,
好的。 [NOISE]现在，
[NOISE] um, lecture two and so for today,
[NOISE]嗯，今天讲课二，等等，
we're gonna keep on talking about things you can do with
我们将继续谈论你可以做的事情
Word Vectors and say a little bit at the end about Word sensors.
Word Vectors和最后一点关于Word传感器的说法。
So, in more detail, [NOISE] um,
所以，更详细的，[NOISE]嗯，
I'm gonna say a bit more about, um, Word2Vec.
我会更多地谈一下，嗯，Word2Vec。
I'm gonna have a sort of a very brief excursion on optimization, um,
我会对优化进行一次非常简短的游览，嗯，
but then I sort of want to explain a bit more of the space of what
但后来我想解释更多的空间
people have done and can do with dense word representations.
人们已经完成并可以使用密集的单词表示。
So I am gonna say something about
所以我要说些什么
count-based approaches to capturing meaning and how do they work.
基于计数的方法来捕获意义以及它们如何工作。
I'm gonna talk for a bit about a,
我要谈谈一下，
a different model of Word Vectors which was the GloVe model that,
一个不同的Word Vectors模型，它是GloVe模型，
um, as a post-doc of mine, um,
嗯，作为我的博士后，嗯，
Jeffrey Pennington and, uh,
杰弗里潘宁顿，呃，
me worked on a couple of years ago,
我几年前工作过，
um, talk some about evaluation,
嗯，谈谈评估，
really quite dominant theme on a lot of what
在很多东西上真正占据主导地位的主题
we do on natural language processing is how do we,
我们在自然语言处理上做的是我们怎样，
how do we evaluate things and how much do we trust our evaluations,
我们如何评估事物以及我们对评估的信任程度，
um, and then say a little bit about, um, word sensors.
嗯，然后再说一下，嗯，文字传感器。
I have a sort of a goal here which is that by the end of the class,
我有一个目标，就是在课程结束时，
um, you should actually sort of understand, um,
嗯，你真的应该理解，嗯，
enough of the lay of the land that you could
足够的土地，你可以
read papers about word vectors such as the ones that
阅读关于单词向量的论文，例如那些
are in the syllabus and actually understand
是在教学大纲中，实际上是理解的
them and where they're coming from and roughly how they work.
他们和他们来自哪里以及他们的工作方式。
And so, you know, if you really wanna minimize
所以，你知道，如果你真的想最小化
work for your c- this class, you could think, "I,
为你的c-这堂课工作，你可以想，“我，
I know everything I need to know after the first week and I'm gonna
我知道第一周后我需要知道的一切，我会
do a final project on word vectors and I'll be okay."
做一个关于单词向量的最终项目，我会没事的。“
Um, and you know, you could actually do that,
嗯，你知道，你实际上可以这样做，
I mentioned during the wo- um,
我在女儿期间提过，
class, um, a couple of recent pieces of work on word vectors.
上课，嗯，最近几个关于单词向量的工作。
On the other hand, um,
另一方面，嗯，
doing things with word vectors as a fairly mined out areas,
用词向量作为一个相当开采的区域做事，
so you're probably better off, um,
所以你可能会更好，嗯，
also listening to some of the later parts of the class.
还听了班上后来的一些部分。
Okay. So, remember we had this idea of Word2Vec,
好的。所以，记住我们有Word2Vec的想法，
so it was an iterative updating algorithm that learned, um,
所以这是一个迭代更新算法，学到了，嗯，
these vector representations of words,
这些矢量表示的单词，
then in some sense capture their meaning and the way it worked was we kinda
然后在某种意义上捕获它们的意义和它的工作方式是我们有点
moved position by position through a corpus and each point in time,
通过语料库和每个时间点按位置移动位置，
we had a center word here into and it's trying to predict
我们在这里有一个中心词，它正试图预测
the words around that by having
通过拥有这些词语
a probability distribution over words will occur around that,
围绕这个词的概率分布会发生在那里，
and that probability distribution is defined simply in terms
并且简单地用术语来定义概率分布
of the.product of the word vectors via the Softmax function.
通过Softmax函数得到的单词向量的产品。
And so, what we wanna do is change those vectors in
所以，我们想做的是改变那些向量
a way that this gives good probability predictions,
这种方式可以提供良好的概率预测，
that gives as high probability as possible to words that you tend to see in the context.
这使得您倾向于在上下文中看到的单词具有尽可能高的概率。
And so, just to drill that in a little bit more, you know,
所以，只需再多练一点，你知道，
what we actually have is we have two matrices, right?
我们实际拥有的是我们有两个矩阵，对吗？
We have for center words,
我们有中心词，
we have a matrix where for each word in our vocabulary,
我们有一个矩阵，对于我们词汇表中的每个单词，
we have a vector, um, and at this,
我们有一个矢量，嗯，在这，
this is probably as good a point as any to say that it
这可能与任何说法一样好
turns out that all the major deep learning packages,
事实证明，所有主要的深度学习包，
TensorFlow, PyTorch, etc., for their word vectors,
TensorFlow，PyTorch等，用于它们的单词向量，
the word vectors are represented as rows.
单词向量表示为行。
If you've done a bunch of math classes,
如果你做过一堆数学课，
that might not be what you would expect.
这可能不是你所期望的。
You might have expected the other way around,
你可能已经预料到了另一种方式，
but they all put them in rows.
但他们都把它们排成一排。
So we can have rows for our,
所以我们可以有我们的行，
um, so we have six words and a five dimensional vector each.
嗯，所以我们每个都有六个单词和一个五维向量。
Okay. And then, we have this outside, um,
好的。然后，我们在外面，嗯，
matrix where we also have a second, um,
矩阵，我们还有第二个，嗯，
vector for each word which is this representation in context.
每个单词的向量，这是在上下文中的表示。
Um, so when we have a particular center word here,
嗯，所以当我们在这里有一个特定的中心词时，
word four, you know,
第四个字，你知道，
when we're doing our computations,
当我们进行计算时，
we're taking a.product between v_4 and each row of
我们在v_4和每一行之间取一个产品
U and that's then giving us a vector of dot product scores.
那时那就给我们一个点积分数的向量。
And so, then after that,
然后，那之后，
we're running Softmaxes on each of those numbers doing it
我们在每个这样的数字上运行Softmaxes
element-wise and that's been giving us
元素方面，这一直在给我们
a probability distribution over words in the context.
上下文中单词的概率分布。
Um, and the sort of things to notice there, um,
嗯，还有那些需要注意的事情，嗯，
which hopefully you noticed last time,
希望你上次注意到，
but to make sure you noticed that,
但要确保你注意到了，
um, you know, we've just got one probability distribution, right?
嗯，你知道，我们只有一个概率分布，对吧？
So in terms of what words we predict,
所以就我们预测的词而言，
we're predicting exactly the same probability distribution, every position.
我们预测每个位置的概率分布完全相同。
We've sort of saying the most likely word one to the left
我们有点说左边最可能的单词
is whatever it is house or most likely word to the left is house,
不管它是什么房子，或者最左边的字是房子，
three to the left is house,
左边三个是房子，
the one to the right should be house too, right?
右边的那个也应该是房子，对吧？
So, it's sort of no sort of find us a prediction,
所以，有点像我们预测的那样，
it's just an overall kind of
这只是一种整体的
probability distribution of words that are likely to occur in my context.
在我的上下文中可能发生的单词的概率分布。
So, all we're asking for is a model that gives
所以，我们要求的只是一个给出的模型
reasonably high probability estimates to all words that
所有单词的概率估计值相当高
occur in the context of this word relatively often,
相对经常出现在这个词的上下文中，
is nothing more to it than that.
没有什么比这更重要了。
And that's part of why it's sort of surprising when you've got
这就是为什么当你得到它时会有点惊讶的部分原因
such a simplistic thing that it seems like at the end of the day,
这样一个简单的事情，似乎在一天结束时，
it can end up capturing so much about
它最终可以捕获这么多
the meanings of words and aspects of the meanings of words,
单词的意义和单词意义的方面，
like in the examples I've just showing you in the IPython Notebook.
就像我刚刚在IPython Notebook中展示的例子一样。
Um, and [NOISE] there's one other thing I was gonna say, oh yeah,
嗯，[NOISE]我还会说另外一件事哦，是的，
one other thing I was gonna say was the other thing that might occur to you from this is,
我要说的另一件事是你可能发生的另一件事是，
um, well, wait a minute,
嗯，好吧，等一下，
there was like that and-and,
有那样的 - 和，
and-of that occur all the time.
并且 - 这一直在发生。
Um, so that means every word must have a high dot product with words like that and of and,
嗯，这意味着每个单词必须有一个高点产品，其中包含类似的单词和
um, they get their probabilities right.
嗯，他们的概率正确。
And the first answer to that is, "Yup, that's true."
而第一个答案是，“是的，这是真的。”
And it turns out that all word vectors, [NOISE] um,
事实证明，所有的单词向量，[NOISE]嗯，
have a very strong prob- word probability component that reflects that.
有一个非常强大的概率概率成分反映了这一点。
And I mean, one of the things that some workers discuss,
我的意思是，一些工人讨论的事情之一，
so on the readings,
所以在读数上，
there are two papers from Sanjeev Arora's group in Princeton and one of
来自普林斯顿的Sanjeev Arora小组有两篇论文
those papers sort of discusses, um, this probability,
那些论文有点讨论，嗯，这个概率，
high frequency effect and your crude way of [NOISE] actually
实际上，高频效应和你的粗暴[NOISE]方式
fixing this high frequency effect is that normally, um,
固定这种高频效果通常是，嗯，
the first, um,
第一个，嗯，
the first biggest component in
中国第一大组成部分
your word vectors is actually a frequency effect and if you just lop it off,
你的单词向量实际上是一个频率效果，如果你只是把它丢掉，
you can make your semantic similarities better.
你可以使你的语义相似性更好。
Um, but there are other things that we do to sort of deal with high frequencies.
嗯，但我们还有其他一些事情可以解决高频问题。
Okay, so we get these lovely spaces that I've shown some of.
好的，所以我们得到了这些可爱的空间，我已经展示了一些。
But I'll make one more remark. Um.
但我还会再说一遍。嗯。
Yeah, so did I say this last time? Oh, oh.
是的，我上次这么说了吗？哦，哦。
Um, my remark anyway is that,
嗯，无论如何我的评论是，
um, we show all these two-dimensional pictures.
嗯，我们展示所有这些二维图片。
They're exceedingly, exceedingly misleading because in these pic,
它们非常极具误导性，因为在这些照片中，
two-dimensional pictures, you know,
二维图片，你知道，
you have these effects that if, you know,
你有这些影响，如果，你知道，
Samsung is close to Nokia,
三星接近诺基亚，
it has to be over here and then it has to be far away from words that are over here.
它必须在这里，然后它必须远离这里的文字。
Um, whereas you might sort of also want to have the effect that
嗯，你也可能想要产生这样的效果
Nokia is close to Finland for a different reason,
由于其他原因，诺基亚离芬兰很近，
um, and you can't do that in two-dimensional, um,
嗯，你不能用二维的方式做到这一点，嗯，
vector spaces but, you know, one of the, um,
矢量空间，但是，你知道，其中一个，嗯，
most of the properties of high dimensional vector spaces are very unintuitive,
高维向量空间的大多数属性非常不直观，
and one of the ways that they're unintuitive is in a high dimensional vector space,
并且它们不直观的方式之一是在高维向量空间中，
a word can be close to lots of other words in different directions.
一个单词可以接近很多不同方向的其他单词。
Um, okay. So um,
嗯，好的。嗯，
we sort of started to talk about how we went about learning these word vectors.
我们开始讨论如何学习这些单词向量。
I'm sort of going to take about a five minute detour into optimization.
我有点花费大约五分钟的时间来进行优化。
Now, this isn't really an optimization class,
现在，这不是一个真正的优化类，
if you want to learn a lot about optimization.
如果你想学习很多关于优化的知识。
Well you can learn more about optimization if you do
如果你这样做，你可以了解更多有关优化的信息
229 and if you do something like Stephen Boyd's optimization class,
229如果你像Stephen Boyd的优化课那样做，
you can learn a lot of optimization but this is
你可以学到很多优化但是这样
sort of really baby optimization but just to make sure everyone's on the same page,
有点真正的宝贝优化，但只是为了确保每个人都在同一页上，
here are three slides.
这是三张幻灯片。
Right, so what we did at the end,
是的，所以我们最后做了什么，
what we did over there,
我们在那边做了什么，
where I apologized that my writing was too small,
我道歉，我的写作太小了，
but that will give you the chance to when doing homework too and you have to
但这样你就有机会做作业了，你必须这样做
write that out to work it out for yourselves and learn more in the process.
写出来为自己解决问题并在此过程中学习更多。
Right, so what we had was a cost function that we wanted to
是的，我们所拥有的是我们想要的成本函数
minimize and so what we did was we did our bit of
最小化，所以我们做了什么，我们做了一点点
calculus to calculate the gradient of the cost function with respect
微积分计算成本函数的梯度
to our word vectors which were our variables theta and then what we want to do is say,
我们的单词向量是我们的变量theta然后我们想要做的是说，
well if we take a small step in
好吧，如果我们迈出一小步
the direction of the negative of the gradient that will be taking us down,
渐渐消极的方向会让我们失望，
down hill in this space and we want to keep on
在这个空间下山，我们想继续
doing that and sort of head to the minimum of our space.
这样做，并在我们的空间最小化。
I mean, of course in our high multi-dimensional space,
我的意思是，当然在我们高度多维的空间里，
you know, it might not be a nice smooth curve like this.
你知道，这可能不是一个很好的平滑曲线。
It might be a horrible and non-convex curve but that's just the idea.
它可能是一个可怕的非凸曲线，但这只是一个想法。
So, essentially we're saying we've got the old parameters,
所以，基本上我们说我们有旧的参数，
we work out the gradient of the objective function using those old parameters.
我们使用那些旧参数计算出目标函数的梯度。
We multiply that by a small alpha which is
我们将它乘以一个小的alpha
our step size or learning rate because we only want to move a
我们的步长或学习率因为我们只想移动一个
little bit each time because if back here,
每次都有点，因为如果回到这里，
if we sort of said downhill is this way and said,
如果我们说下坡是这样的，并说，
"Great let's go a long way that way."
“很棒，让我们走很长的路。”
You could kind of completely overshoot,
你可能会完全超调，
so we only want to go a little bit each time.
所以我们每次只想做一点点。
So we normally have a small learning rate alpha and so we
所以我们通常有一个小的学习率alpha，所以我们
subtract a small multiple of the gradient and we,
减去渐变的一小部分，我们，
from the old parameters and we get
从旧的参数，我们得到
our new parameters and that sort of effectively being worked out,
我们的新参数和那种有效的方法，
component wise as is shown below,
组件如下所示，
that we're just doing that to each of the partial derivatives and then,
我们只是对每个偏导数做这个，然后，
that our hope is that that will let us gradually walk down this surface.
我们希望这会让我们逐渐走下这个层面。
Now, if you actually did this,
现在，如果你真的这样做了，
it would be unbelievably bad for the kind of
对于那种情况来说，这将是令人难以置信的糟糕
systems that we build and there's a lot of work on
我们构建的系统，并且有很多工作要做
clever optimization but the most basic thing
聪明的优化，但最基本的事情
which you definitely need to know is that well,
你肯定需要知道的是，
our objective function here,
我们的目标函数在这里
J of theta was a function of our entire corpus, right?
theta的J是我们整个语料库的函数，对吗？
And to get this to work well,
为了让这个工作顺利，
the first thing you want to do is,
你要做的第一件事是，
you know collect a few billion words of your favorite language and then say,
你知道收集几十亿字你喜欢的语言，然后说，
"Go and build a Word2Vec model for me, " and so,
“为我建立一个Word2Vec模型”，所以，
if you have to evaluate
如果你必须评估
a billion center words and maybe then to- for each of 10 billion context words,
十亿个中心词，然后可能为每个100亿个上下文词，
if you have a window size of five and you- so you have to do these sort of 10 billion um,
如果你有一个5的窗口大小你 - 所以你必须做这100亿美元，
Softmax calculations before you work out what your gradient is,
在计算出渐变之前的Softmax计算，
that you're going to be having your computer compute for a quite a long time before
您将在很长一段时间内完成计算机计算
you make one little step in the gradient and so things are going to go so, so slowly.
你在渐变中迈出了一小步，所以情况会如此缓慢。
So, no one does that in deep learning systems.
所以，在深度学习系统中没有人这样做。
Um, so what people- everyone does is use
嗯，所以每个人都做的就是使用
stochastic gradient descent and in stochastic gradient descent,
随机梯度下降和随机梯度下降，
we sample our window in the simplest case.
我们以最简单的方式对窗口进行采样。
We, just for this one window,
我们，只为这一个窗口，
work out an estimate of the gradient and we use it as a parameter update.
计算出梯度的估计值，并将其用作参数更新。
So, this is sort of an amazingly,
所以，这有点令人惊讶，
amazingly noisy estimate of
令人惊讶的嘈杂估计
the gradient but it sort of doesn't matter too much because as soon as we've done it,
渐变，但它有点无关紧要，因为我们一做到这一点，
we're going to choose a different center word and do it again and again,
我们要选择一个不同的中心词并一次又一次地做，
so that gradually we sort of approach what we would have gotten if we'd sort
所以，如果我们排序，我们会逐渐接近我们会得到的东西
of looked at all of the center words before we took any steps,
在我们采取任何步骤之前看了所有的中心词，
but because we take steps as we go,
但是因为我们采取措施，
we get to the minimum of the function orders and magnitude more quickly.
我们更快地达到函数指令和幅度的最小值。
So thi- this shows the simplest case where we're just sampling one window.
所以这显示了最简单的情况，我们只是采样一个窗口。
In practice, that's not what we normally do.
在实践中，这不是我们通常做的事情。
We normally sample as- a small bunch,
我们通常采样为一小群，
you know, order of approximately 32 or 64.
你知道，大约32或64的顺序。
Um, so if we have a sample that's bigger,
嗯，如果我们有一个更大的样本，
that's generally referred to as a mini-batch and we
这通常被称为小批量和我们
calculate a gradient estimate from the mini-batch.
从小批量计算梯度估计。
Um, so that has two advantages.
嗯，这样有两个好处。
One advantage is that you kind of get less noisy estimates of
一个优点是你可以减少噪音估计
the gradient because you've kind of averaged
渐变，因为你有一定的平均值
over a bunch of examples rather than just using one,
在一堆例子而不是仅仅使用一个，
but the second advantage,
但第二个优势，
which is the one why we really care,
这就是我们真正关心的原因，
is if we want our computations to go fast when we're using a GPU,
如果我们在使用GPU时希望计算速度快，
that you need to get parallelization of doing the same operation a whole bunch of
你需要得到一大堆相同操作的并行化
times and then you gain a lot by using
时间，然后你通过使用获得了很多
a mini-batch of 64 examples or something like that.
一小部分64个例子或类似的东西。
Um, and you don't have to but you know,
嗯，你不必，但你知道，
it turns out the details of the guts of the hardware that you know,
它证明了你知道的硬件内容的细节，
it isn't- [inaudible] GPUs, you know, they have these,
它不是 -  [听不清] GPU，你知道，他们有这些，
whatever they have inside them,
无论他们在里面有什么，
there in powers of two.
有两个权力。
So, you get better speedups if you use batches like 32 or 64,
因此，如果您使用32或64等批次，您可以获得更好的加速
rather than just deciding that 42 is still your favorite number from
而不只是决定42仍然是你最喜欢的数字
high school [LAUGHTER] and you're going to use that as the size of your mini-batch.
高中[大笑]，你将使用它作为你的小批量的大小。
Okay. um, yeah here's
好的。嗯，是的，这里
one other interesting thing which
另一个有趣的事情
actually has some optimization details in it, it turns out.
事实证明，其中有一些优化细节。
Um, if you think of these um,
嗯，如果你想到这些，
doing stochastic gradients with word vectors,
用词向量做随机渐变，
that's actually very different to
这实际上是非常不同的
some other deep learning problems like vision deep learning problems.
其他一些深度学习问题，如视觉深度学习问题。
Because for either a single window or even a sort of a reasonably sized mini-batch,
因为对于单个窗口甚至是一种合理大小的小批量，
it will turn out that those mini-batch,
结果那些小批量，
mini-batch only has, you know,
你知道，小批量只有
relatively speaking a handful of words in it, right?
相对而言，其中有几句话，对吧？
So, if you have mini-batch of size 32 and a window size of ten,
所以，如果你有32个小批量和10个窗口大小，
you know, probably there are only about a 100,150 different words in it.
你知道，它中可能只有大约100,150个不同的单词。
Um, but yet we're building this model over
嗯，但我们正在构建这个模型
a vocabulary of quarter of a million words or something like that.
一个百万字的词汇或类似的词汇。
So, just about all of the elements in this vector are zero.
所以，这个向量中的所有元素都是零。
Um, and so, um,
嗯，等等，嗯，
we sort of really have this very sparse um,
我们真的有这个非常稀疏的嗯，
perimeter update and so, um,
周边更新等等，嗯，
that sort of suggests that we actually probably um,
那种暗示我们实际上可能是，
want to sort of only update the word vectors that
想要只更新那些单词向量
appear and then the question is whether you can achieve that, right?
出现，然后问题是你是否能实现这一点，对吗？
The dumb way to do it, is you just have this matrix that's normally,
这样做的愚蠢方法是你只需要这个矩阵，
nearly all zeros and you say add
几乎所有的零，你说添加
those two matrices together and there you go and then the question is,
那两个矩阵在一起，你去，然后问题是，
can you actually have a sparse matrix update which only updates
你真的可以有一个只更新的稀疏矩阵更新
the certain rows of the matrix that contain
包含的矩阵的某些行
the words that you've entered and do things much faster?
你输入的字数和做得更快的话？
And if you're doing something even cleverer like doing
如果你做的事情比做更聪明
distributed computation over multiple computers and sharing your parameters,
在多台计算机上分布式计算并共享您的参数，
well then definitely you just sort of only want to update
那么你肯定只是想要更新
the word vectors that you've actually been getting a parameter estimate for.
您实际上已获得参数估计的单词向量。
So, there's sort of some details there but I'm
所以，那里有一些细节但是我
going to skip past them for more details, um.
要跳过它们了解更多细节，嗯。
Right. So, a couple of people asked afterwards, yeah,
对。所以，有几个人事后问，是的，
why are there these two word vectors that sort of center and the outside one?
为什么这两个单词向量中心和外部单词？
And, I mean the answer to that is,
而且，我的意思是答案是，
it makes that math I showed you easy, right?
这让数学我很容易，对吧？
So that if, um,
所以，如果，嗯，
if you do it as I showed you, well,
如果你像我给你看的那样做，好吧，
you know, for working out, um,
你知道，为了锻炼，嗯，
the partial derivatives for the center word.
中心词的偏导数。
It's just as I showed you, it's easy.
正如我向你展示的那样，这很简单。
Um, but if you use only one set of word vectors,
嗯，但是如果你只使用一组单词向量，
well then the same word,
那么同一个词，
that's the center word,
这是中心词，
will be one of the choices for
将是其中一个选择
the context word when you're working out that Softmax for the context word.
当您为上下文单词设计Softmax时的上下文单词。
And then you'll get these terms that are then
然后你会得到这些术语
squared terms in terms of the two references,
两个参考文献中的平方术语，
so that same word,
所以同一个词，
and that makes your math more difficult.
这会让你的数学更加困难。
Um, so it's sort of just a practical thing,
嗯，所以它只是一个实用的东西，
um, in the end.
嗯，最后。
I mean it sort of doesn't make very much difference,
我的意思是它并没有太大的区别，
because if you sort of think about it since you're going along through all the,
因为如果你经历了所有的考虑，你会想到它，
um, positions, you know.
嗯，职位，你知道。
What was a center word at one point is immediately afterwards
之后立刻就是一个中心词是什么
a context word of what used to be a context word,
曾经是上下文单词的上下文单词，
which is now the center word.
这是现在的中心词。
So, sort of doing the same computations because, you know,
所以，有点做同样的计算，因为，你知道，
the dot product is symmetric actually,
点积实际上是对称的，
um, all over again.
嗯，一遍又一遍。
So, they get pretty similar vector representations.
因此，他们获得了非常相似的矢量表示。
So, it seems like in general you can get the best results
所以，似乎一般来说你可以获得最好的结果
by averaging what comes out for your two vectors,
通过对你的两个向量进行平均，
and you end up with just one vector per word.
你最终每个单词只有一个向量。
Okay, more substantively, um,
好的，更实质性的，嗯，
if you go to the word2vec paper,
如果你去word2vec论文，
you'll discover that there's sort of more to word2vec that they
你会发现他们对word2vec有更多的了解
define as sort of a family of word2vec models.
定义为word2vec模型的一类。
And there are so two main parts of that family.
这个家庭有两个主要部分。
Um, firstly, there's a choice between the Continuous Bag of Words model,
嗯，首先，在Continuous Bag of Words模型之间有一个选择，
and the skip-grams model.
和skip-gram模型。
And what I presented with the skip-grams models.
我用skip-gram模型提出了什么。
So, in the skip-grams model,
那么，在skip-gram模型中，
you've got one center word and you're trying to
你有一个中心词，你正试图
predict all the words in context one at a time.
一次一个地预测上下文中的所有单词。
For the Continuous Bag of Words model it's the opposite.
对于Continuous Bag of Words模型，情况正好相反。
You've got all of the outside words and you're trying to use all of them,
你已经掌握了所有外部词汇，而你正在尝试使用所有这些词语，
though considered independently like a Naive Bayes model to predict the center word.
虽然像Naive Bayes模型一样被独立考虑来预测中心词。
Um, and then the second one is, um,
嗯，然后第二个是，嗯，
the way I presented learning this was
我学习这个的方式是
the method that's using the so called Naive Softmax.
使用所谓的Naive Softmax的方法。
So, therefore when we are wanting to work things out,
因此，当我们想要解决问题时，
we were sort of saying okay we want probability estimates for the context words,
我们有点说好，我们想要上下文单词的概率估计，
and so we're just going to sum over
所以我们只是总结一下
the whole vocabulary and we'll come up with these probability estimates.
整个词汇表，我们将提出这些概率估计。
Um, in practice, that turns out to be a sort of
嗯，实际上，结果证明是一种
a bad idea because that would also make things mega slow.
一个坏主意，因为这也会使事情变得非常缓慢。
So, in homework two,
所以，在作业二，
coming up next week, um,
下周即将到来，嗯，
you will get to implement a much more practical, um,
你会实现一个更实用的，嗯，
way of doing this which they present in the word2vec papers, right?
他们在word2vec论文中提出这样做​​的方式，对吧？
So, the problem is,
所以，问题是，
if we're using this equation that we use to do the calculus,
如果我们使用这个我们用来做微积分的方程，
that down in this denominator here,
这个分母在这里，
we're doing the sum over the entire vocabulary.
我们正在对整个词汇进行总结。
So, if you have a vocabulary of a quarter million words,
所以，如果你有25万字的词汇，
we're sort of doing a quarter of a million dot products and
我们有点像25万个点产品
exponentials and adding them all to work out that denominator.
指数并将它们全部加入以计算出分母。
And that sort of seems uh,
那种似乎呃，
sort of a really bad idea if you want things to be fast.
如果你想让事情变得更快，那就是一个非常糟糕的主意。
Um, so, um, Tomas Mikolov and
嗯，所以，嗯，Tomas Mikolov和
colleagues came up with this idea of negative sampling would be near enough.
同事想出了这种负抽样的想法就足够了。
And so the idea of negative sampling,
所以负抽样的想法，
is we're going to train binary logistic regressions instead.
我们是要培训二进制逻辑回归。
And so, we're going to train one binary logistic regression
因此，我们将训练一个二元逻辑回归
for the actual word observed what's in the numerator,
对于实际的单词，观察分子中的内容，
and you want to give high probability to the word that was actually observed.
并且你想给出实际观察到的单词的概率很高。
And then, what we're going to do,
然后，我们要做什么，
is we're going to sort of randomly sample a bunch of other words,
我们是要随机抽样一堆其他的话，
they're the negative samples and say they weren't the ones that were actually seen.
他们是负面样本，并说他们不是实际看到的样本。
So, you should be trying to give them as low a probability as possible.
所以，你应该尽量给它们尽可能低的概率。
Okay, so, um, the sort of notation that
好的，嗯，那种符号
they use in the paper is sort of slightly different to the one I've used.
他们在论文中使用的与我使用的略有不同。
They actually do maximization not minimization,
他们实际上做最大化而不是最小化，
and that's the equation which I'll come back to.
这就是我要回到的等式。
Um, though before we do that here's the sigmoid function.
嗯，虽然在我们这之前这里是sigmoid功能。
So, the sigmoid function is normally written like this,
所以，sigmoid函数通常是这样编写的，
one over one plus E to the minus X.
一个加一个加E到负X.
But, um, essentially,
但是，嗯，基本上，
the sigmoid function is like a binary case of the Softmax function, right?
sigmoid函数就像是Softmax函数的二进制情况，对吗？
That we have two possible outcomes, yes or no,
我们有两种可能的结果，是或否，
and that you're sort of again got an input that is any real number,
并且你有点再次获得任何实数的输入，
and it's mapping it onto a probability distribution between
它将它映射到两者之间的概率分布
zero and one which represents these two binary outcomes.
零和一个代表这两个二元结果。
And to the extent that the number is positive,
并且在数量为正的范围内，
it kind of ceilings to one and negative goes down to zero.
它有一种天花板，负面可以降到零。
Okay, so with this time,
好的，所以这个时候，
we're going to take the dot for- for the good word,
我们要拿点来换一个好词，
we're going to take the dot product of the two vectors,
我们将采用两个向量的点积，
shove it through our sigmoid function
通过我们的S形函数推动它
and then we're going to want that probability estimate,
然后我们想要那个概率估计，
um, to be as high as possible.
嗯，要尽可能高。
So, if I show you this version,
所以，如果我给你看这个版本，
which is just written slightly differently, um,
这只是略有不同，嗯，
to look as much as possible like the notation that we used last time,
像我们上次使用的符号一样尽可能多地看，
here is our new objective function for using negative sampling.
这是我们使用负抽样的新目标函数。
And we've got two terms,
我们有两个术语，
the first one, um,
第一个，嗯，
is the log of the sigmoid of the observed context word,
是观察到的上下文单词的sigmoid的对数，
the outside words, dot producted with the center word,
外面的单词，用中心词生成的点，
and we're going to want that to be big.
而且我们希望它变大。
Um, and then on the other hand,
嗯，然后另一方面，
um, we've got, um, the,
嗯，我们有，嗯，
um, randomly chosen K words,
嗯，随机选择的K字，
which are just other words,
这只是其他的话，
and we're going to work out dot products between them and the center word.
我们要研究它们和中心词之间的点积。
And we're going to want those to be as small as possible.
而且我们希望那些尽可能小。
Um, note that extra minus sign in there which is causing
嗯，请注意那里造成的额外减号
the sign of the two things to be different, right?
这两件事的标志是不同的，对吧？
So, those are our negative samples.
所以，那些是我们的负面样本。
And for big K, it can be a reasonably modest number,
而对于大K来说，它可能是一个相当适中的数字，
you can just take kind of 10,
你可以采取10种，
15 negative samples and that works pretty fine.
15个负面样本，效果很好。
Um, I said we sort of sampled some words,
嗯，我说我们对一些单词进行了抽样，
um, to be the negative samples.
嗯，是负面样本。
They in particular propose a sampling distribution that helps them along
他们特别提出了一个可以帮助他们的抽样分布
a little in partly dealing with this pro- problem of very frequent words.
稍微部分地处理这个非常频繁的词的问题。
Um, so the starting point of how you sample words is you
嗯，所以你如何采样单词的起点就是你
use what we call the- the unigram distribution.
使用我们称之为unigram的分布。
So, that just means you take words on a large corpus and count up
所以，这只意味着你在一个大型语料库上说话并计算起来
how often each one occurs just as a count of independent words,
每个人出现的频率与独立单词的数量相同，
so there's the called unigram counts.
所以有所谓的unigram计数。
And so you start off with unigram counts,
所以你从unigram计数开始，
but then you raise them to the three quarters power.
但是你把它们提升到四分之三的力量。
And raising to the three quarters power,
并提升到四分之三的力量，
has the effect of, um,
有这样的效果，嗯，
decreasing how often you sample very common words,
减少你采样非常常见的单词的频率，
and increasing how often you sample rarer words.
并增加你采样稀有词的频率。
Okay, um, and that's that.
好的，嗯，就是这样。
Okay, so that's everything about word2vec I am going to say.
好的，这就是我要说的关于word2vec的一切。
Anyone have any last thing.
任何人都有最后的事情。
Yes. [NOISE]
是。 [噪声]
Oh, oh [NOISE]. This is a- sorry Z,
哦，哦[NOISE]。这是对不起Z，
that capital Z is often used as a normalization term and so this is saying,
资本Z经常被用作规范化术语，所以这就是说，
well if you want the probability distribution of words,
如果你想要单词的概率分布，
is you work out this three quarters power of the count
你在计算这四分之三的力量吗？
of the word for every word in the vocabulary and then these
对于词汇表中的每个单词，然后是这些单词
numbers you just sum them up over the vocabulary and it'll be sum
数字你只是将它们总结在词汇表中，它就是总和
total and we're dividing by that so we get a probability distribution.
总和，我们除以那个，所以我们得到概率分布。
Good question because i hadn't explained that.
好问题，因为我没有解释过。
Um, in this class, when you see the letter Z with no explanation,
嗯，在这堂课上，当你看到字母Z没有解释时，
it normally means I am a normalization term to turn things into
它通常意味着我是一个将事情变为现实的标准化术语
probabilities and you sort of iterate over
概率和你的迭代
the numerator term and summing them and divide through.
分子术语并将它们相加并除以。
Any other questions of things I haven't explained or otherwise? Yes.
关于我没有解释过的其他问题或其他问题？是。
So the window [inaudible] that's a [inaudible]
所以窗口[音频不清晰]是[音频不清晰]
Yeah, yes.
是的，是的。
So, [NOISE] what size window do you use?
所以，[NOISE]你使用什么尺寸的窗户？
I'll actually come back to that in a bit and show a little bit of data on that,
我实际上会稍微回过头来展示一些关于它的数据，
but yeah, we haven't done anything about that.
但是，我们还没有做过任何事情。
At the moment we're guessing a window size like five,
目前我们猜测窗口大小为五，
which isn't a bad one um,
这不是一个坏的嗯，
but you know there isn't- there hasn't really been any science behind that, um,
但是你知道没有 - 那背后真的没有任何科学，嗯，
that people treat that as what's then called a hyperparameter which means that um,
人们把它视为当时所谓的超参数，这意味着，嗯，
you try a few different numbers and see which one seems
你尝试了几个不同的数字，看看哪一个看起来
best and that's the one that you use in your future work. Yeah.
最好的，这是你在未来工作中使用的那个。是啊。
Um, [inaudible] three quarters power
嗯，[听不清]四分之三的力量
chosen for any theoretical reason or just because it seems to work in practice?
选择任何理论上的原因还是因为它似乎在实践中起作用？
Um, no. Um, that,
不。嗯，那个，
that was um, also chosen as a hyperparameter and improved performance.
那是嗯，也被选为超参数和改进的性能。
I mean, actually um, you know,
我的意思是，实际上，嗯，你知道，
for this Word2Vec paper, I mean,
对于这篇Word2Vec论文，我的意思是，
you know, it turns out that um,
你知道，事实证明，嗯，
in the actual paper um,
在实际的论文中，
the model looks very- fairly clean but what
该模型看起来非常干净，但是什么
people's discovered when they started digging through the code,
人们在开始挖掘代码时发现了
which to- to their credit they did make available, reproducible research,
他们确实提供了可重复的研究，
that there are actually a whole bunch of tricks
实际上有一大堆技巧
of different things like these hyperparameters of um,
像这些超参数这些不同的东西，
how you sample, and how you wait windows and various things to make the numbers better.
你如何抽样，以及你如何等待窗户和各种事情来改善数字。
So, you know, people play quite a few tricks to make
所以，你知道，人们会玩很多技巧
the numbers go up which aren't particularly theoretical.
数字上升并不是特别理论上的。
Are we good?
我们好吗？
Yeah.
是啊。
[inaudible] [NOISE].
[听不清] [NOISE]。
Ah, sometimes.
啊，有时候。
I so- I- you- so in general for a lot of these sampling things,
我是 - 我 - 你 - 所以一般来说很多这些采样的东西，
it's a bad idea if you're going to be doing multiple passes if you just go bloom,
如果你只是去做多次传球，这是一个坏主意，
bloom, bloom and then bloom, bloom, bloom again,
绽放，绽放，然后绽放，绽放，再次绽放，
that's a bad idea,
这是一个坏主意，
but a common technique a lot of the packages use
但是许多软件包使用的常用技术
is that they do use this shuffling operation at the beginning.
是他们在开始时使用这种改组操作。
So for each epoch,
所以对于每个时代，
they'll shuffle the data randomly and then they'll go through it in sequence and that has
他们会随机地对数据进行随机播放，然后他们会依次对其进行处理
the benefits of faster computation from locality et cetera um,
从本地开始计算速度更快的好处，等等，
while ha- meaning that when you do it differently epoch,
虽然ha-意味着当你做不同的时代，
it will work out differently.
它将以不同的方式运作。
Uh, yeah, yeah.
呃，是的，是的
[inaudible] [NOISE] [inaudible].
[听不清] [NOISE] [听不清]。
That last question I think was talking about taking the mini-batches from the corpus and
我认为最后一个问题是谈论从语料库中获取迷你批次
contrasting whether you actually say sample 20
对比你是否真的说样品20
randomly from the whole corpus versus just sort of working from left to right.
从整个语料库中随机选择，而不是从左到右。
Yes, do you have a question?
是的，你有问题吗？
Um, yeah [inaudible] [NOISE].
嗯，是的[听不清] [NOISE]。
Yeah. So- so you could argue- you could argue
是啊。所以你可以争论 - 你可以争辩
whether or not this was written in the clearest way, but, right.
这是否是以最清晰的方式写的，但是，对。
So, we're making this dot product and then we're negating it
所以，我们正在制作这个点产品，然后我们就是否定它
which is then flipping which side of the space we're on, right?
然后翻转我们所在空间的哪一边，对吗？
Because the sigmoid is symmetric around zero.
因为S形在零附近是对称的。
So, if we've got some dot product um,
那么，如果我们有一些点产品，
and then we negate it,
然后我们否定它，
we're sort of working out a one minus probability and so
我们有点算一个减去概率等等
that's the way in which we're actually for the first um,
这就是我们实际上第一个这样的方式，
for the first time we're wanting the probability to be
我们第一次想要概率
high and then for the negative samples,
高，然后为负样本，
we're wanting their probability to be low.
我们希望他们的概率很低。
Okay, I'll maybe run ahead now.
好的，我现在可能会跑。
Um, so this was an algorithm which um,
嗯，所以这是一个算法，嗯，
sort of you're going through this corpus position by position and you're sort of doing
有点你按位置经历这个语料库位置而你正在做什么
this prediction of words and then you're
这个词的预测然后你就是
updating some parameters and you're learning something and you know,
更新一些参数，你正在学习一些东西，你知道，
by job it seemed to work based on what we saw in the examples,
按工作，它似乎是基于我们在示例中看到的，
but you know, you might have thought um,
但是你知道，你可能想过，
that that was kind of weird right?
那有点奇怪吧？
Look we have this whole big pile of data you know,
看看我们拥有你知道的大量数据，
sort of traditional, I'm thinking of statistics, right?
有点传统，我在考虑统计，对吧？
So you have a big pile of data,
所以你有大量的数据，
you aggregate it and it sort of seems like there are obvious things you could do here.
你聚合它，似乎你可以在这里做一些明显的事情。
You could say, well there's a word like,
你可以说，好吧有一个词，
whatever word we're using, banana.
我们用的任何字，香蕉。
Let's just see what words occur in the context of the gut banana and count
让我们看看在香蕉和计数的背景下会出现什么词
them all up and then we'll be able to use those to predict somehow and you know,
他们全部起来，然后我们将能够用这些来预测，你知道，
those kinds of methods were traditionally
传统上这些方法
used including even with distributed representation techniques.
甚至使用分布式表示技术。
Um, so I want to say a bit about that,
嗯，所以我想说一点，
so you're fully educated and don't sound like one of those people who were
所以你受过充分的教育，听起来不像那些人
aware of no work that happened before 2013 when your network's took off.
意识到在2013年网络启动之前没有发生任何工作。
Um, okay. So, what we could do is we can essentially
嗯，好的。所以，我们能做的就是我们可以
do the same thing as sort of Word2Vec.
做与Word2Vec相同的事情。
We could say there's a five word window around
我们可以说周围有一个五字窗口
each word instance that's often referred to as a word token, right?
每个单词实例通常被称为单词标记，对吧？
So at NLP, we often want to distinguish between a particular kind of type like banana
所以在NLP，我们经常想要区分像香蕉这样的特定类型
or apple versus particular instances
或苹果与特定情况
often in the text and that's referred to as sort of a type token distinction.
通常在文本中，这被称为类型标记的区别。
So we could, um,
所以我们可以，嗯，
look at each um token with a word,
用一个单词看每个um标记，
and the words five around that,
和周围的五个字，
and then we could so start counting up which words occur,
然后我们就可以开始计算出哪些单词出现了，
occur with it and so we can then have a matrix of co-occurrence counts.
随之发生，因此我们可以得到共生计数矩阵。
Um, okay.
嗯，好的。
So, we'll have again,
那么，我们会再来一次，
and I'm going to give me an example of this.
我会举一个这样的例子。
So, normally again you use the five to 10 but you know I can just
所以，通常你再次使用5到10，但你知道我可以
use a window of one to keep my counts very simple and small.
使用一个窗口来保持我的计数非常简单和小。
I ignore left or right just like Word2Vec did,
我像Word2Vec那样忽略了左或右，
and so if I have a teeny baby corpus like this,
所以，如果我有这样一个小小的婴儿语料库，
you know, what I could do,
你知道，我能做什么
is just say here is the matrix of word co-occurrence accounts.
这里只说这是单词共现帐户的矩阵。
So, within my window size of one,
所以，在我的窗口大小一个，
I occurs next to like twice,
我发生在旁边两次，
and that means that like occurs next I twice it's symmetric,
这意味着，就像下一次我发生两次对称，
and all my other accounts here are singletons, um.
我所有的其他账户都是单身人士，嗯。
And so this gives me a big huge sparse matrix of word co-occurrence accounts.
所以这给了我一个庞大的单词共现帐户的稀疏矩阵。
And so one thing that you could do is just use this matrix directly,
所以你可以做的一件事就是直接使用这个矩阵，
because I haven't really got enough data here.
因为我这里没有足够的数据。
But, you know, if you sort of,
但是，你知道，如果你有点，
um, decided that, you know,
嗯，决定，你知道，
the word like is like the word learning,
这个词就像学习这个词，
what you'd do is you'd expect that
你要做的就是你期待的
these two vectors would end up kind of similar to each other.
这两个向量最终会彼此相似。
And [NOISE] they do.
并且[噪音]他们这样做。
So, you can just measure, um,
所以，你可以测量，嗯，
similarity of the vectors directly in terms of these co-occurrence counts.
直接就这些共现计数而言，矢量的相似性。
But, you know, it's a little bit unappealing doing things this way, right?
但是，你知道，用这种方式做事有点不吸引人，对吧？
If you have a quarter million word vocabulary that's where
如果你有25万字的词汇就在哪里
you are in this space where my math is bad,
你在这个数学不好的地方，
but it's in the trillions of the number of cells of this matrix,
但它在这个矩阵的细胞数量的数万亿，
might require a lot of storage.
可能需要大量存储空间。
Though if you're clever and notice that most of the cells were zero and could do
虽然你很聪明并且注意到大多数细胞都是零并且可以做到
some clever sparse matrix representation might take a little bit less.
一些聪明的稀疏矩阵表示可能会少一些。
Um, your classification models might have sparsity issues cause, you know,
嗯，你的分类模型可能有稀疏性问题因为你知道，
a lot of those cells aren't present and so it might not be very robust.
许多细胞不存在，因此它可能不是很强大。
And so those are traditional answer to all of these things which is well,
所以这些都是对所有这些事情的传统回答，这很好，
maybe we could have that big co-occurrence counts matrix
也许我们可以有那么大的共现计数矩阵
and somehow reduce its dimensionality of just, um,
并以某种方式减少它的维度，嗯，
find a corresponding low dimensional matrix which preserves,
找到保留的相应低维矩阵，
uh, most of the information, um,
呃，大部分信息，嗯，
in the original matrix and, you know,
在原始矩阵中，你知道，
maybe we'll reduce things to a dimensionality of somewhere around the size 25 to a 1,000,
也许我们会将事物减少到25到1000左右的某个维度，
um as is done with Word2Vec.
就像使用Word2Vec一样。
So, there's sort of a standard most common way of doing
所以，有一种标准的最常见的做法
this dimensionality reduction and you don't really have to understand all the math,
这种维数降低，你真的不需要了解所有的数学，
but you get to play with this and homework one which is, um,
但是你可以玩这个和家庭作业，这是，嗯，
for any matrix you can do what's called the singular value decomposition, um,
对于任何矩阵，你可以做所谓的奇异值分解，嗯，
which is a way you can take an arbitrary matrix and decompose it into three matrices, um,
这是一种你可以采用任意矩阵并将其分解为三个矩阵的方法，嗯，
where the center one is diagonal and has what- in it what are
中心的一个是对角线，其中有什么
called singular vectors which are weightings of the different dimensions.
称为奇异向量，它们是不同维度的权重。
So, they decrease in size as you go downwards.
因此，随着您的下降，它们的尺寸会减小。
And then these two U and V are then
然后是这两个U和V.
orthogonal bases corresponding to the rows and columns.
对应于行和列的正交基。
And so in particular,
特别是，
it's even simpler than the case where we just have these word-word vectors,
它甚至比我们只有这些单词矢量的情况更简单，
because you have a square matrix and so they are effectively the same.
因为你有一个方阵，所以它们实际上是一样的。
But, you know, for the general case, um,
但是，你知道，对于一般情况，嗯，
although you get these sort of full orthogonal bases,
虽然你得到了这些完全正交的基础，
you then have these bits sort of don't really
然后，你有这些有点不真的
matter cause they end up being used for nothing when you work out the product.
因此，当你计算出产品时，它们最终会被用尽。
Um, and then if you want to reduce the dimensionality, what you say is,
嗯，如果你想减少维数，你说的是，
throw away the smallest singular values which remember there are in decreasing
抛弃最小的奇异值，记住它们在减少
size and that means you're then effectively
大小，这意味着你有效
throwing away rows and columns of these other matrices.
扔掉这些其他矩阵的行和列。
And then it says,
然后它说，
behold I've now reduced these things to
我现在已经把这些东西减少了
a two-dimensional representation from
来自的二维表示
the original three-dimensional representation and that's referred to as
原始的三维表示，即所谓的
the reduced SVD and the classic result is in terms of least squares error in
减少的SVD和经典结果就最小平方误差而言
estimation that this- the product of these three things will give X k which is the best,
估计这三个东西的产物会给出最好的X k，
um, k- rank k approximation to the original X in terms of,
嗯，k-等级k近似于原始X，
uh, X squared least squares criterion.
呃，X平方最小二乘准则。
So, we could do this and we could build word vectors.
所以，我们可以做到这一点，我们可以构建单词向量。
So, I can, um,
所以，我可以，嗯，
make use of, um,
利用，嗯，
NumPy's SVD function and I can throw into it,
NumPy的SVD功能，我可以投入其中，
um, matrices and, um,
嗯，矩阵，嗯，
I can make word vectors.
我可以制作单词向量。
And these ones look really bad, but hey,
这些看起来很糟糕，但是，嘿，
I give it a dataset of three centers [LAUGHTER] and it's not exactly a fair comparison.
我给它一个三个中心的数据集[大笑]，这不是一个公平的比较。
But- so this technique was in, um,
但是 - 这个技术是，嗯，
popularized around, um, the turn- the turn of the millennium.
转向千禧年，转向千禧年。
It generally, um, went for
一般来说，嗯，去了
some word applications under the name of latent semantic analysis or
一些单词应用程序以潜在语义分析或
latent semantic indexing and the idea was that you could have
潜在的语义索引和想法是你可以拥有的
these semantic directions that you are
你是这些语义指导
finding in this low dimensional space that had meaning.
找到这个有意义的低维空间。
And people worked with it quite a bit for techniques
人们对技术的处理非常有用
like t- trying to do information retrieval
喜欢t-尝试进行信息检索
using these LSA approximations and it sort of worked a bit.
使用这些LSA近似值，它有点工作。
It kind of never really worked very well I think,
我觉得它从来没有真正起作用，
um, and so it never sort of hugely caught on.
嗯，所以它永远不会被大肆抓住。
Um, but it's- the methods kind of continued to be explored actually mainly in the sort of
嗯，但是 - 这种方法实际上主要是在某种程度上进行探索
COG psych- COGS psych community where people were doing things with word meaning.
COG psych-COGS心理社区，人们用文字意义做事。
And there's this sort of kind of interesting, um,
而且有这种有趣的，嗯，
the [NOISE] to the literature that there was this guy Doug Rohde, um,
[NOISE]文献中有这个人Doug Rohde，嗯，
who, um, did a PhD at CMU, um, in 2005.
谁，嗯，2005年在CMU获得博士学位。
And basically what he discovered was,
基本上他发现的是，
look if rather than just using raw counts,
看看是否而不仅仅是使用原始计数，
I start doing quite a bit more in terms of,
我开始做的更多，
you know, fiddling with the counts,
你知道，摆弄计数，
I can start to produce results that are much better.
我可以开始产生更好的结果。
So, rather than using low counts,
所以，而不是使用低计数，
you have to do something to deal with those very high-frequency words.
你必须做些什么来处理那些非常高频率的词。
So, one idea is you could log scale them which
所以，一个想法是你可以记录缩放它们
is also commonly used in information retrieval.
也常用于信息检索。
Another idea is you could just use something like,
另一个想法是你可以使用像，
uh, a ceiling function,
呃，天花板功能，
so you take the minimum of X,t for t set and that some number like around 100.
所以你取t的最小值为X，t取一些数字，比如大约100。
Um, he had- he used the idea which was also another of the hacks that was put into
嗯，他曾经 - 他使用了这个想法，这也是另外一个黑客入侵
the Word2Vec was rather than just treating the whole window the same that you should,
Word2Vec不仅仅是对整个窗口的处理方式与你应该的相同，
um, count words that are closer more.
嗯，算一些更接近的词。
So, in Word2Vec, they sample closer words more commonly than further away words.
因此，在Word2Vec中，他们比更远的单词更频繁地采样更接近的单词。
Um, in his system, you're sort of having to have
嗯，在他的系统中，你有点必须拥有
a differential count for closer words et cetera.
更接近单词的差别计数等。
And then, um, compared to any of that rather than using counts at all,
然后，嗯，与任何相比，而不是使用计数，
he then started using Pearson correlations which
然后他开始使用Pearson相关性
helped and set they're sometimes negative and he decided that it helped,
帮助和设置他们有时是负面的，他认为它有帮助，
um, if you then got rid of the negative values.
嗯，如果你那么摆脱负值。
So, in- in some sense,
所以，在某种意义上，
this sounds like a bag of hacks,
这听起来像一袋黑客，
um, but on the other hand,
嗯，但另一方面，
he was able to show that, you know,
他能够表明，你知道，
these transformed counts could actually then give
这些转化的计数实际上可以给出
you very useful word vectors as I'm about to show.
你将要展示的非常有用的单词向量。
And- well, we have to realize that actually in slightly different forms,
而且，我们必须意识到实际上形式略有不同，
several of these exact same counts are actually being used in Word2Vec as well.
其中几个完全相同的计数实际上也在Word2Vec中使用。
Do you hear that?
你听到了吗？
Yeah. Were they [inaudible].
是啊。他们是[音频不清晰]。
Yeah. So, so that's an- I'm about to show exactly that.
是啊。所以，这就是 - 我将要准确地表明这一点。
Um, that's actually a really interesting little,
嗯，这实际上是一个非常有趣的小事，
um, bit of the data.
嗯，有点数据。
So, you know, what, um, yeah,
那么，你知道，嗯，是的，是的，
so the, the thing- if you do that,
那么，事情 - 如果你这样做，
you not only get word similarities pretty good.
你不仅得到相似的相似之处。
Let me show you this example which is cleaner.
让我告诉你这个更清洁的例子。
Um, so this- the precise idea of
嗯，所以这个 - 确切的想法
evaluating with analogies was not something that had really been developed.
用类比进行评估并不是真正发展起来的。
So, that was actually something that Marsh Mikolov, um, suggested.
所以，这实际上是Marsh Mikolov，嗯，建议的东西。
But actually, um, Doug Rohde made this, um,
但实际上，嗯，Doug Rohde做了这个，嗯，
really interesting observation which was- he said, look,
非常有趣的观察 - 他说，看，
"Once I do these kind of transformations to
“一旦我做了这些转变
improve the semantic representation of my word vectors,
改善我的单词向量的语义表示，
look this really interesting property emerges.
看看这个真正有趣的物业出现了。
Um, that what you find is that there is semantic vectors
嗯，你发现的是有语义向量
are which basically linear components in my carefully-constructed space.
在我精心构造的空间中基本上是线性组件。
So, here we have the sort of, um,
所以，我们有这样的，嗯，
verb to the doer of the verb direction,
动词对动词方向的动词，
drive, driver, um, clean,
开车，司机，嗯，干净，
janitor, swim, swimmer, learn,
看门人，游泳，游泳，学习，
teacher or teach, teacher,
老师或教师，老师，
doctor, treat, priest, pray.
医生，治疗，牧师，祈祷。
I mean, you know, it's not exactly perfect,
我的意思是，你知道，它并不完美，
you know, there's a little bit of wiggle there, right?
你知道吗，那里有一点点摆动，对吧？
But, you know, roughly it's completely clear that there's sort of a direction
但是，你知道，大致完全清楚的是有一个方向
in the space that corresponds to- from a verb to the doers of a verb.
在动词与动词的实施者对应的空间中。
Um, and yeah, so he [inaudible] - he-
嗯，是的，所以他[听不清]  - 他 -
no one had thought of this idea of doing the analogies and tests.
没有人想到这种类比和测试的想法。
But the thing in retrospect that's obvious is,
但回想起来的事情很明显，
if you can construct a vector space that has this linearity property,
如果你可以构造一个具有这种线性属性的向量空间，
then you're definitely gonna do well in analogy.
那么你肯定会做类比的好。
So, effectively he had invented a vector space that do
所以，实际上他发明了一个矢量空间
well in analogies because this means that you've got
很好地类比，因为这意味着你已经得到了
this direction which is the doer and then you can immediately
这个方向是行动者然后你可以立即
say that's the doer vector which you can get from subtracting clean from swimmer.
说这是你可以通过从游泳运动员中减去干净而获得的实施者。
And the- Right. So, it's clean from janitor.
而且 - 对。所以，它从看门人那里干净了。
And then we can add it on to swim and we'll get somewhere close to swimmer.
然后我们可以将它添加到游泳中，我们将会到达游泳者附近。
Um, so his space actually did do that.
嗯，所以他的空间确实这样做了。
And so, um, this is- so the,
所以，嗯，这是 - 所以，
the moral in some sense is,
在某种意义上，道德是，
if you have- if you kind of do carefully control accounts and so on,
如果你有 - 如果你有点谨慎控制帐户等，
that conventional methods can also give you good word vector spaces and- I mean,
传统的方法也可以给你很好的单词向量空间 - 我的意思是，
so that was actually the starting off point for our work on GloVe.
所以这实际上是我们在GloVe上工作的起点。
Um, so that essentially,
嗯，基本上，
there had been these two schools of work.
曾经有过这两个学派。
Um, there had been the school of work that had
嗯，曾经有过的工作学校
been explored more in COG psych than anywhere else,
在COG心理学中探索的比其他任何地方都要多，
which had been based on counting and transforming counts.
这是基于计数和转换计数。
And, you know, it had some advantages or it seemed it had some advantages, right?
并且，你知道，它有一些优势，或者它似乎有一些优势，对吧？
That, um, you're making sort of efficient use of statistics as you're using
那个，嗯，你在使用时正在有效地使用统计数据
the global statistics of the whole matrix directly to estimate things.
整个矩阵的全局统计直接估计事物。
Um, and at that poi- up until then,
嗯，直到那时为止，
it had really only being used to capture word similarity, um,
它真的只被用来捕捉单词的相似性，嗯，
and a lot of it had suffered from disproportionate im- importance given to large counts.
并且其中很多都遭受了大量不成比例的不重要。
But Doug Rohde, he had sort of started to show how to solve both of these problems.
但道格罗德，他有点开始展示如何解决这两个问题。
And so on the other hand,
等等，
there had been these neural network methods
曾经有过这些神经网络方法
which are kind of direct prediction methods that
这是一种直接的预测方法
we're defining that probability distribution and trying to predict the words that occur.
我们正在定义概率分布并试图预测发生的单词。
And they had some advantages, right?
他们有一些优势，对吗？
The fact that your sampling means that you're not going to run out of memory hopefully.
你的抽样意味着你不会希望你的内存不足。
I know we've had some memory problems with homework one, but in principle,
我知道我们家庭作业存在一些记忆问题，但原则上，
you're not as bad memory position and if you have to
你没有那么糟糕的记忆位置，如果你必须这样做
construct a huge matrix because you're going linearly,
构造一个巨大的矩阵，因为你是线性的，
um, but, you know, since you're doing it sample by
嗯，但是，你知道，因为你正在做样品
sample it's inefficient use of statistics, um.
样本是统计数据的低效使用，嗯。
Okay. And so, but on the other hand Mikolov's work it performed perfectly.
好的。所以，但另一方面，Mikolov的工作表现完美。
Not perfectly, but really well.
不完美，但非常好。
Um, so this is sort of led into this work,
嗯，这有点像这项工作，
um, that Jeffrey Pennington, um,
嗯，Jeffrey Pennington，嗯，
Richard Socher [inaudible] can we sort of combine these ideas
Richard Socher [听不清]我们可以将这些想法结合起来
and sort of have some of the goodness of the neural net methods,
并且有一些神经网络方法的优点，
um, while trying to do things with some kind of count matrix.
嗯，同时尝试用某种计数矩阵做事。
And so in particular, um,
尤其如此，嗯，
we wanted to get the result in
我们想得到结果
a slightly less hacky way that you want to have components of meaning
你希望拥有意义组成部分的方式稍微逊色一些
being linear ope- linear operations in
是线性运算的
the vector space that they're just some effective or adding or something like this.
向量空间，它们只是一些有效或添加或类似的东西。
And so the crucial observation of this model was that we could use
所以这个模型的关键观察是我们可以使用
ratios of co-occurrence probabilities to encode meaning components.
共现概率与编码意义成分的比率。
And so the idea here is,
所以这里的想法是，
if you have a word like ice and
如果你有像冰一样的话
you say how often the thing's going to co-occur with that,
你说这件事经常与之共同发生，
well solid should co-occur a lot and gas shouldn't.
固体应该共同发生很多，气体不应该。
But well water is also going to co-occur a lot and some random word won't occur much.
但井水也会同时出现很多，一些随机的词也不会发生太多。
If you have, oops.
如果你有，哎呀。
If you have steam,
如果你有蒸汽，
you get the opposite pattern with solid and gas, right?
你得到了与固体和气体相反的模式，对吧？
But so the thing to notice is,
但需要注意的是，
it's not enough to just have large by itself because large
仅仅因为大而单独拥有它是不够的
appears both here and here or small appears there and there,
出现在这里或这里或小到那里出现，
the thing that's interesting and sort of the difference between
有趣的东西和它们之间的区别
these components in there indicating a meaning component.
这些组件在那里表示含义成分。
And so we can get it that if we look at the ratio of co-occurrence probabilities.
因此，如果我们看一下共现概率的比例，我们就可以得到它。
And so for the ratio of co-occurrence probabilities this is a dimension of
因此，对于共现概率的比率，这是一个维数
meaning and where for other words and this sort of ratio cancels out to about one.
意思和其他词语的位置和这种比例取消大约一个。
And so in this slide I've moved so it's not how my
所以在这张幻灯片中我已经移动了所以不是我的
small and large that these are actually actual counts from a corpus.
从小到大，这些实际上都来自语料库。
So we roughly get dimension of meaning between
所以我们大致得到了意义之间的维度
solid and gas are the ones coming out
固体和天然气是出来的
as about one because they are not the dimension of meaning.
至于一个，因为它们不是意义的维度。
And so, it seems like what we want is we want to have ratio of
所以，似乎我们想要的是我们想要的比例
co-occurrence probabilities become linear and our space.
共现概率变为线性和我们的空间。
And then we're in a good business.
然后我们的业务很好。
And so that's what we want to set about doing.
这就是我们想要做的事情。
Well, how can you do that?
那你怎么能这样做？
Well, the way you can do that,
好吧，你可以这样做，
is by if you can make the dot products equal to the log of the co-occurrence probability,
如果你可以使点积等于共现概率的对数，
then immediately you get the fact that when you have
然后你马上得到了这样的事实
a vector difference it turns into a ratio of the co-occurrence probabilities.
矢量差异变成共现概率的比率。
And so, essentially the whole of the model is that we
因此，基本上整个模型就是我们
want to have dot products or logs of co-occurrence probabilities.
想拥有共现概率的点积或对数。
And so, that's what we do.
所以，这就是我们的工作。
So, here is our objective function here
所以，这是我们的目标函数
and it's made to look a little bit more complicated.
它看起来有点复杂。
But essentially we've got this squared loss here
但基本上我们在这里得到了这个平方损失
and then we wanting to say the dot-product should be as similar
然后我们想说点积应该是相似的
as possible to the log of
尽可能的日志
co-occurrence probability and so you'll they'll
共现概率，所以你会他们
be lost to the extent that they're not the same,
失去他们不一样的程度，
but we kind of complexify it a little by putting in bias terms for both of the two words.
但是我们通过对这两个词加上偏见来稍微复杂化一点。
Because maybe the word is just overall common and likes to
因为这个词可能只是整体而且喜欢
co-occur things or uncommon or does end.
共同发生或不常见或结束。
And then we do one more little trick because every [inaudible] does tricks to make the performance
然后我们又做了一个小技巧，因为每个[音频不清晰]都会制作一些技巧来表现
better is that we also use this f-function in front,
更好的是我们也在前面使用这个f函数，
so that we're sort of capping the effect that
所以我们有点限制那种效果
very common word pairs can have on the performance of the system.
非常常见的单词对可以对系统的性能产生影响。
Okay. And so that gave us the GloVe model of word vectors.
好的。所以这给了我们GloVe的单词向量模型。
And theoretically, the interest of this was,
理论上，这的兴趣是，
you know, a lot of the preceding literature had been there had
你知道，以前的很多文献都有
been these count methods and there had been these prediction methods.
一直是这些计数方法，并有这些预测方法。
And the hope was that this could sort of unify the
希望是这可以统一
two by showing you how you could have a method that
两个通过向您展示如何拥有一个方法
is estimated simply of a count matrix but it's done in the same kind of
估计只是一个计数矩阵，但它是在同一类型中完成的
iterative loss based estimation method that's
基于迭代损耗的估计方法
used for the neural methods to get good word vectors.
用于神经方法来获得良好的单词向量。
And this also worked to give good word vectors.
这也有助于提供良好的单词向量。
So here's GloVe results for the word frog.
所以这里是青蛙这个词的GloVe结果。
And frogs and toad are obvious.
青蛙和蟾蜍很明显。
But there are these different kinds of words, uh,
但是有这些不同的词，呃，
various kinds of pretty tree frogs and things like that.
各种漂亮的树蛙和类似的东西。
Okay. Um, so I'll then go from here and say a little
好的。嗯，所以我会从这里开始说一点
bit more about some of the work on evaluating word vectors.
更多关于评估单词向量的一些工作。
And this is maybe also a chance just talk a little bit about evaluation altogether.
这也许是一个机会，只谈一点关于评估。
So, normally in NLP when we do a valuation,
那么，通常在NLP进行估值时，
the first thing that comes up is intrinsic versus extrinsic evaluation.
首先出现的是内在与外在的评价。
So, normally if there's something we trying to do like model, um,
所以，通常如果我们试图像模型那样做，嗯，
word similarity with word vectors or we're trying to, um,
与单词向量的单词相似性或我们正在尝试，嗯，
put parts of speech on words or something,
把词性放在单词或东西上，
we can just have an intrinsic evaluation of saying how good a job did you get.
我们可以对你说你的工作有多好有内在的评价。
Are you guessing the right part of speech?
你猜对了吗？
Are you putting synonyms close together?
你把同义词放在一起吗？
And that's sort of normally very easy to do and fast to compute.
而这通常很容易做到并且计算速度快。
And it's useful to do because it helps us understand the system.
这样做很有用，因为它有助于我们理解系统。
On the other hand, a lot of the time those intrinsic evaluations,
另一方面，很多时候那些内在的评价，
it's not very clear where- where they're having done well on that task is really going to
目前还不是很清楚他们在这项任务上做得好的地方确实会发生
help us build the amazing natural language understanding robots
帮助我们建立令人惊叹的自然语言理解机器人
that we so ardently desire.
我们如此热切地渴望。
Um, so, people are also very interested in extrinsic evaluations.
嗯，人们对外在评价也很感兴趣。
And so extrinsically is then saying well suppose you use
因此，外在地说，假设你使用
this new stuff in a real system doesn't make performance go up.
真实系统中的这些新东西并没有使性能提升。
And it's then sort of definitional what counts
然后它就是那些重要的定义
to you as a real system that normally that's
你作为一个真正的系统，通常是那样的
meaning it's some application that human beings actually care about and liked to use.
这意味着它是人类真正关心和喜欢使用的一些应用。
So that's something like web search, or question answering,
这就像网络搜索或问答，
or phone dialog system or something like that, um,
或电话对话系统或类似的东西，嗯，
hat you can put it into that system and the numbers get- go up.
你可以把它放进那个系统，数字就会上升。
So, that seems what you want to do.
所以，这似乎是你想要做的。
You want to have stuff that works in real tasks.
你想拥有适合实际任务的东西。
Of course, there are sort of on the other hand a lot of things are a lot harder than.
当然，另一方面，有很多事情要比很多事情困难得多。
So much more work to do such an evaluation and run different variance of a system.
还有更多的工作要做这样的评估，并运行不同的系统方差。
And even when the results, uh,
即使结果，呃，
poor or great sometimes it's hard to diagnose.
贫穷或伟大有时很难诊断。
You know, if- if your great new word vectors don't work better in the system, you know,
你知道，如果你的伟大的新单词向量在系统中不能更好地工作，你知道，
it might be for sort of some extraneous reason about
它可能是出于某些无关紧要的原因
how the system was built at sort of hiding all your magic.
系统是如何构建的，隐藏着你所有的魔力。
And if you just change the rest of the system and suddenly show its good effects.
如果你只是改变系统的其余部分并突然显示其良好的效果。
So, it's kind of hard to do,
所以，这很难做到，
um, sort of, um,
嗯，有点，嗯，
apportionment of goodness and badness Okay.
好与坏的分配好的。
So, um, so, today I'm mainly going to say a little bit more about
所以，嗯，今天我主要是要多说一点
these intrinsic word vector evaluations that we've talked about.
我们已经讨论过的这些内在的单词向量评估。
So we've talked quite a bit about these analogies.
所以我们已经谈了很多关于这些类比的话题。
So if we're actually working out the analogies,
所以，如果我们真的在计算类比，
it turns out that normally what people are doing is working out
事实证明，通常人们正在做的事情正在发挥作用
a cosine distance and angle between, um,
余弦距离和角度之间，嗯，
different word candidates, um,
不同的候选人，嗯，
to work out which is the word that solves the analogy which
找出哪个是解决类比的词
is an Norbert little tiny wrinkle of difference there.
诺贝尔那里有一点不同的皱纹。
And there's also one other trick that people commonly use.
还有人们常用的另一个技巧。
They forbid the system from returning one of the three word she put
他们禁止系统返回她提出的三个单词中的一个
into the analogy Okay.
进入类比好吧。
But nevertheless, so, this is something that you can evaluate.
但是，所以，这是你可以评估的东西。
Here now some GloVe visualizations.
现在这里有一些GloVe可视化。
And so these GloVe visualizations show exactly the same kind of
因此，这些GloVe可视化显示的完全相同
linearity property that Doug Rohde discovered which means that analogy's work.
Doug Rohde发现的线性属性意味着类比的工作。
Sort of by construction,
按建筑类别划分，
because our vector space wanted to make meaning components linear.
因为我们的向量空间想要使意义成分成为线性
So, this is then, um,
那么，这就是，嗯，
showing a gender display.
显示性别显示。
This is showing one between companies and their CEOs, kind of cool.
这显示了公司和他们的CEO之间的一种，很酷。
And you can also do more syntactic facts.
而且你也可以做更多的句法事实。
So this is showing, um,
所以这表明，嗯，
positive comparative and superlative of adjectives.
形容词的积极比较和最高级。
Yeah. So, Tomas Mikolov came up with this idea of doing these analogy tasks.
是啊。因此，Tomas Mikolov提出了做这些类比任务的想法。
And so he built a data-set with a lot of analogies in it.
因此他构建了一个包含许多类比的数据集。
It's sort of- it's a bit of a weirdo data-set because it's sort of tests a few
它有点像一个古怪的数据集，因为它是一些测试
random different things which may have been things that his system worked well on, um,
随机不同的东西可能是他的系统运作良好的东西，嗯，
but you know, it tests countries and capitals,
但是你知道，它会测试国家和首都，
country, cities and states, countries and currency.
国家，城市和州，国家和货币。
So there are a bunch of semantic things that tests.
所以有一堆语义测试。
And then there are some, um,
还有一些，嗯，
syntactic things that tests so bad, worst,
测试如此糟糕，最差的句法事物
fast fastest for superlatives.
最快速的最高级。
But, you know, even some of the ones I was showing before, you know,
但是，你知道，甚至我之前展示过的一些，你知道，
there's no- there's no Obama is to
没有，奥巴马没有
Clinton kind of ones that are actually in this evaluation set.
克林顿那种实际上属于这个评估集的人。
Um, here's a big table of results,
嗯，这是一个很大的结果表，
um, that comes from our GloVe paper.
嗯，来自我们的GloVe论文。
So not surprisingly the GloVe paper perform best in this evaluation.
因此，GloVe论文在本次评估中表现最佳也就不足为奇了。
Because that was our paper. Um, [LAUGHTER]
因为那是我们的论文。嗯，[大笑]
[LAUGHTER] But I mean perhaps- you know,
[笑声]但我的意思是 - 你知道，
perhaps the things to start to notice is,
也许要开始注意的事情是，
yeah, if you just do a plain SVD on counts.
是的，如果你只是做一个简单的SVD计数。
You know that that works abominably badly for these, um, analogy tasks.
你知道这对于这些类比的任务来说非常糟糕。
But, you know, kind of as Doug Rohde showed,
但是，你知道，就像Doug Rohde所说的那样，
if you start then doing manipulations of the count matrix before you do an SVD,
如果您在进行SVD​​之前开始操作计数矩阵，
you can actually start to produce
你真的可以开始生产了
an SVD based system that actually performs quite well on these tasks.
基于SVD的系统，实际上可以很好地完成这些任务。
Um, you know, not badly against other things.
嗯，你知道，对其他事情并没有太糟糕。
Um, other things that you will discover,
嗯，你会发现的其他事情，
right at the top there are a 100 dimensional ones,
在顶部有一个100维的，
and at the bottom there are some 1000 dimensional ones,
在底部有一些1000维的，
and other 300 dimensional ones.
和其他300维的。
At least when you're training on a big amount of text,
至少当你训练大量的文字时，
bigger dimensionality definitely works better.
更大的维度肯定更好。
And I'll come back to that in a minute.
我会在一分钟后再回过头来看看。
Um, the amount of text makes a difference as well, right?
嗯，文字的数量也有所不同，对吧？
So we're going up from- so one to 1,5 billion words at the beginning,
所以我们从一开始就上升到15亿字，
to these ones down here are being trained over 42 billion words of text,
对这些人来说，正在培训超过420亿字的文字，
and perhaps unsurprisingly, the 42 billion words of texts ones work better.
也许不出所料，420亿字的文本更好用。
Um, so it's big data.
嗯，这是大数据。
Um, here are a couple more steps from this paper.
嗯，这是本文的几个步骤。
So this is a graph of dimensionality and what the performance is.
所以这是一个维度图和性能图。
So for the three lines the green one's semantic,
所以对于三行绿色的语义，
the blue one's the syntactic analogies and so red's the overall score.
蓝色的是句法类比，所以红色是整体得分。
So sort of what you see is up to dimensionality
所以你看到的东西取决于维度
300 things that clearly increasing quite a bit,
300件事明显增加了很多，
and then it gets fairly flat,
然后它变得相当平坦，
which is precisely why you find a lot of word vectors,
这正是你找到很多单词向量的原因，
um, that are of dimensionality 300.
嗯，具有维数300。
Um, this one's showing what window size.
嗯，这个显示什么窗口大小。
So this is sort of what we talked about symmetric on both sides window size,
所以这就是我们谈到的双面窗口尺寸对称性，
and as it goes from 246810.
从246810开始。
And sort of what you see is,
而你看到的是，
if you use a very small window like two, that actually works.
如果你使用像2这样的非常小的窗口，那实际上是有效的。
That the, the syntactic prediction is stronger because well,
那个，句法预测更强，因为，
syntactic effects are very local.
句法效果非常局部。
Whereas as you go out,
你外出的时候
the semantic prediction gets better and better.
语义预测变得越来越好。
Actually this syntactic gets a bit better as well,
实际上这个句法也变得更好了，
but it's especially the semantic that gains.
但它尤其是获得的语义。
Um, the right graph shows that if you only use context on one side,
嗯，右边的图表显示，如果你只在一边使用上下文，
um, your numbers aren't as good.
嗯，你的数字不太好。
Okay, um, so, I sort of just wanted to sort of sneak in a little cameos of a couple of,
好吧，嗯，所以，我有点想偷偷溜进几个小小的浮雕，
um, recent bits of work,
嗯，最近的一些工作，
as sort of a first of what things people are doing,
作为人们正在做的第一件事，
um, with word vectors.
嗯，用词向量。
Um, so this one, um,
嗯，所以这个，嗯，
was actually by two Stanford people.
实际上是两个斯坦福人。
Um, now the best- this would be the best story.
嗯，现在是最好的 - 这将是最好的故事。
If I could say that this was a final project,
如果我能说这是最后的项目，
um, in this class last year,
嗯，去年上课，
but unfortunately that's not true.
但不幸的是，这不是真的。
This paper has nothing to do with this class [LAUGHTER].
本文与本课程[笑声]无关。
But it-- right.
但它 - 对。
Um, Zin Yin and Yuanyuan,
嗯，Zin Yin和Yuanyuan，
um, actually had, um,
嗯，实际上有，嗯，
some sort of clever and very mathy ideas,
某种聪明而又非常狡猾的想法，
where they're using matrix perturbation theory.
他们在哪里使用矩阵扰动理论。
Um, and sort of just showing how, um,
嗯，还有点只是展示如何，嗯，
dimensionality in word vectors actually sort of feeds into the bias-variance trade-off.
单词向量中的维度实际上是对偏差 - 方差权衡的馈送。
If you've seen that,
如果你看过，
um, in other parts of machine learning.
嗯，在机器学习的其他部分。
And I'm not even going to attempt to explain their paper.
而我甚至都不会试图解释他们的论文。
Um, but here it is,
嗯，但在这里，
that they did really well with this paper,
他们用这篇论文做得很好，
they gone all talk in Europe's from it.
他们在欧洲谈论它们。
Um, and so- but there's sort of
嗯，等等 - 但是有点儿
an interesting result of what you see with these word vectors,
你用这些单词向量看到的有趣结果，
which is in a way kind of surprising.
这在某种程度上令人惊讶。
So this is showing doing word vector dimensions from zero up to 10,000.
所以这显示了从零到10,000的单词矢量维度。
So we're going way higher than we talked about before.
所以我们比以前谈过的要高。
And so what you discover which people have known for ages is,
所以你发现哪些人已经知道多年了，
that there's sort of a little blip that somewhere around two or 300,
有两点或三点左右的小点，
which seems to optimize performance.
这似乎优化了性能。
So, I've used those sizes.
所以，我已经使用了这些尺寸。
But the thing that they were sort of doing a lot of their theory about,
但他们做了很多关于他们的理论的事情，
and it's kind of surprising is, well,
令人惊讶的是，嗯，
surely if you have a humongous humongous number, like,
当然，如果你有一个巨大的数字，如，
if you are using 10,000,
如果你使用10,000，
um, dimensional vectors, you know,
嗯，维数向量，你知道，
you're trying to estimate another two orders of magnitude more numbers for every word,
你试图为每个单词估计另外两个数量级的数字，
surely things should just fall apart, um,
当然事情应该崩溃，嗯，
because you've got hopelessly many parameters relative to
因为相对于你而言，你已经绝望了许多参数
the amount of training data that you're trying to estimate these numbers from.
您尝试估算这些数字的训练数据量。
And so the interesting result that they show is,
所以他们展示的有趣结果是，
that things don't fall apart.
事情不会崩溃。
Um, and that you can essentially go out to these huge huge dimensionalities,
嗯，你基本上可以走出这些巨大的空间，
and the performance stays flat.
并且表现保持平稳。
And that they've got a lot of theory,
他们有很多理论，
sort of for predicting why that that's actually going to end up being the case.
有点预测为什么这实际上最终会成为现实。
Um, yeah.
嗯，是的
So for training these models iteratively,
因此，为了迭代地训练这些模型，
this is- orange is showing, um, GloVe training.
这是 - 橙色正在展示，嗯，GloVe培训。
You know, they keep on getting better for a while.
你知道，他们会在一段时间内保持良好状态。
So you know, just go out,
所以你知道，出去吧
go sleep and see in the morning how it's doing, right?
睡觉，早上看它是怎么做的，对吧？
So that if you were running it, um,
所以，如果你正在运行它，嗯，
for 24 hours your numbers are better than if you only ran it for six hours.
24小时你的数字比你只运行6个小时更好。
Um, and that's true for a lot of deep learning models, sorry.
嗯，对于很多深度学习模型来说都是如此，对不起。
So this is the key reason why you don't want
所以这就是你不想要的关键原因
to start your assignment the night before it's due.
在到期前一晚开始你的任务。
Because even if you program it perfectly,
因为即使你完美地编程，
you might just not have enough time for it to run,
你可能没有足够的时间来运行，
um, so that you produce good numbers at the end of it.
嗯，这样你就可以在结尾处产生好的数字。
Um, okay. Uh, yeah so,
嗯，好的。呃，是的，
so couple of more, um,
所以还有几个，嗯，
things, on that, um.
那些东西，嗯。
Yes. So, um, what are we showing here?
是。那么，嗯，我们在这里展示什么？
So these are again semantics in tactic and overall numbers.
所以这些又是战术和整体数字的语义。
So there are sort of two things that are sort of being mixed together here.
所以有两种东西在这里混合在一起。
One is, if we just look at the overall numbers,
一个是，如果我们只看一下整体数字，
they're highest over here, um,
他们在这里最高，嗯，
which is this 42 billion Common Crawl web-pages corpus,
这是这个420亿共同爬网网页语料库，
that gives us the highest overall number.
这给了我们最高的总数。
But there's sort of something else that's interesting in this graph, which is,
但是这个图中有一些其他有趣的东西，
um, that using Wikipedia works frequently well.
嗯，使用维基百科经常运作良好。
So that you actually find that 1,6 billion tokens of Wikipedia works
因此，您实际上发现了维基百科的16亿个令牌
better than 4,3 billion tokens of News-wire newspaper article data.
新闻报道文章数据优于43亿美元。
And so I, I think that's sort of actually make sense,
所以我，我认为这实际上是有道理的，
which is well, you know,
哪个好，你知道，
the job of encyclopedias is to just sort of
百科全书的工作就是这样
explain concepts and how they relate to each other, right?
解释概念以及它们如何相互关联，对吧？
So that encyclopedias are
所以百科全书是
just much more expository text that show all the connections between things,
更多的说明性文本显示了事物之间的所有联系，
whereas newspapers in general aren't trying to expose at how things fit together.
而一般而言，报纸并不试图揭露事物如何融合在一起。
They're just telling you about, you know,
他们只是告诉你，你知道，
who got shot dead last night or something like that, right?
昨晚谁被枪杀了，对吧？
So, um, so this is sort of interesting fact, um,
所以，嗯，所以这是一个有趣的事实，嗯，
that this Wikipedia data kind of really,
这个维基百科的数据确实如此，
it sort of is differentially useful, um,
它有点不同，嗯，
for, um, making word vectors.
因为，嗯，制作单词向量。
And you know, in fact, you know,
而且你知道，事实上，你知道，
when we did very well without GloVe word vectors and lots of people use those.
当我们在没有GloVe单词向量的情况下做得很好并且很多人使用它们。
You know, I think actually one of the reasons why they work so well is that
你知道，我认为他们工作得很好的原因之一就是
the original word2vec vectors that Google distributes are built only on Google News data,
Google发布的原始word2vec向量仅基于Google新闻数据构建，
where else sort of have this,
在哪里有这个，
um, Wikipedia data inside them.
嗯，维基百科里面的数据。
Okay, um, rushing ahead.
好吧，嗯，赶紧前进。
Um, yes, so the- there's all the work on analogy,
嗯，是的，所以有关于类比的所有工作，
but the other more basic evaluation is this one of capturing similarity judgments.
但另一个更基本的评估就是捕捉相似性判断。
And I haven't said much about this, but you know,
我没有多说这个，但你知道，
there is this sort of large sub-literature in the psychology community,
在心理学界有这种大型的子文献，
where people have wanted to model humans judgments of similarity.
人们想要模仿人类对相似性的判断。
So like a good psych person, what you do,
所以，像一个好心理的人，你做的，
is you find your classroom of Psych one undergrads,
你找到了一个心理学本科的班级，
and you show them pairs of words and say rate
然后你向他们展示一对单词并说出率
these things for similarity on a scale of one to 10.
这些东西的相似性在1到10的范围内。
And lots of that data has been collected,
并收集了大量的数据，
and you work out the mean over human beings,
你解决了人类的意思，
and they give numbers like this of tiger and cat, 7,35.
他们给出了像老虎和猫这样的数字，7,35。
Tiger's similar to Tiger 10, book and paper,
Tiger类似于Tiger 10，书和纸，
plane and car, stock and phone,
飞机和汽车，股票和电话，
stock and CD, and you get numbers.
股票和CD，你得到数字。
So then, what we're doing is wanting to say,
那么，我们正在做的就是想说，
well let's use distance in the space to map directly onto these similarity judgments,
好吧，让我们利用空间中的距离直接映射到这些相似性判断，
and how well does it map?
它的映射程度如何？
And so that's sort of similarity judging has
所以这种相似性判断有
also then being used for evaluating these systems.
然后用于评估这些系统。
So again, here are a lot of models.
所以，这里有很多模型。
This is again from our GloVe paper.
这再次来自我们的GloVe论文。
But so there are these various similarity data-sets.
但是有这些不同的相似性数据集。
So one of the best-known ones that I had on the slide before is this, um, Wordsim 353.
所以我之前在幻灯片上最着名的就是这个，嗯，Wordsim 353。
It has 353, um,
它有353，嗯，
different ones in it,
不同的，
and so you are sort of then modeling a correlation
因此，您可以对相关性进行建模
between your judgments of similarity and the ones that came from the human beings.
在你的相似性判断与人类的判断之间。
Okay. Two more things I want to say. Um, yes.
好的。还有两件事我想说。嗯，是的。
So, we had that problem right at the beginning
所以，我们一开始就遇到了这个问题
of Clinton and how that could be various people.
克林顿以及那可能是各种各样的人。
And that's perhaps in some sense the simplest case of words being ambiguous,
从某种意义上说，这可能是最简单的单词含糊不清的情况，
when you have names which have reference to different people.
当你的名字引用不同的人。
Um, but it's not only true of names.
嗯，但这不仅仅是名字。
So by and large,
总的来说，
words in human languages are ambiguous and have lots of meanings.
人类语言中的单词含糊不清，含义多种多样。
Um, that's especially true of common words.
嗯，对于常见词汇尤其如此。
They always have lots of meaning.
他们总是有很多意义。
It's especially true of words that have existed for a long time.
对于长期存在的词语尤其如此。
It's not true of new very technical words, you know, carcinoma.
对于新的非常技术性的词语，你知道癌症是不正确的。
I think that only has one meaning.
我认为这只有一个含义。
Um, but, you know,
嗯，但是，你知道，
if you think of any relatively, um,
如果你想到任何相对的，嗯，
common word and starts, um,
常用词和开头，嗯，
scratching your head for a moment,
挠了一下头，
you'll find it has lots of meanings.
你会发现它有很多含义。
I- maybe this isn't even such a common word,
我 - 也许这甚至不是一个常见的词，
but my random word I've got here is Pike.
但我在这里的随机词是派克。
Um, pike has lots of meanings,
嗯，派克有很多含义，
it has meanings like?
它有什么意义？
Fish.
鱼。
Fish, it's a kind of fish, yeah.
鱼，它是一种鱼，是的。
So there's a fish that's a pike.
所以有一条鱼是长矛。
What else is a pike?
还有什么是梭子鱼？
A large spear.
一把大矛。
Yes, so a large spear is a pike.
是的，所以大矛是长矛。
Other kinds of pike's?
其他种类的梭子鱼？
Gymnastics move.
体操动作。
It's a road.
这是一条路。
Gymnastics move or in diving move.
体操运动或潜水运动。
It's a road.
这是一条路。
Um, yeah. Um, so there are lots of meanings.
嗯，是的嗯，所以有很多含义。
Um, there are other meanings.
嗯，还有其他的含义。
Um, in Australian English,
嗯，澳大利亚英语，
pike is also used as a verb to mean,
派克也被用作动词，意思是，
um, to pull out from doing something.
嗯，退出做某事。
Like, "We were all going to go out to a nightclub later, but Joe piked."
就像，“我们以后都会去一家夜总会，但乔嘲笑道。”
[LAUGHTER] Um, I don't think that usage is common in this country,
[笑声]嗯，我不认为这个国家的用法很常见，
but, um, you can try that, um. [LAUGHTER]
但是，嗯，你可以尝试一下，嗯。 [笑声]
Right. But lots of meanings and, you know,
对。但很多意思，你知道，
this isn't only true of the word pike, right?
这不仅仅是派克这个词，对吧？
Pick any other simple word, right?
选择任何其他简单的词，对吗？
You can pick a word like shell or field or house or make,
你可以选择像shell或field或house或make这样的单词，
you know, they have lots of meanings when it comes down to it.
你知道，它归结为它时有很多含义。
So, you know, but, uh,
所以，你知道，但是，呃，
how can this work if we just have one meaningful words?
如果我们只有一个有意义的词，这怎么可行呢？
And that's the interesting question and it was something that
这是一个有趣的问题，它就是那个问题
[NOISE] we were actually interested in early on.
[NOISE]我们实际上对它很感兴趣。
So, I'm even before the Word2Vec paper came out back in 2012,
所以，我甚至在2012年Word2Vec论文发布之前，
um, we were playing around, um,
嗯，我们在玩耍，嗯，
with neural word vectors and, um, we thought,
用神经词向量和嗯，我们想，
boy this is so broken having only one,
这个男孩只有一个，
um, cents, for a word.
嗯，美分，一句话。
Why don't we come up with a model that has multiple sensors for a word?
为什么我们不提出一个具有多个传感器的模型呢？
And so we did that and we did it in a pretty crude way,
所以我们这样做了，我们以粗暴的方式做到了，
I guess, [NOISE] um,
我猜，[NOISE]嗯，
the way we did it is say,
我们这样做的方式是说，
well, let's for each common word,
好吧，让我们为每个常用词，
let's cluster all the contexts in which it occurs.
让我们聚集它发生的所有上下文。
And then we'll see if there seem to be
然后我们会看看是否有
multiple clear clusters by some criterion for that word.
通过该词的某些标准的多个清晰簇。
And if so, we'll just sort of split the word into pseudo words.
如果是这样，我们只会把这个词分成伪词。
So, if it seems like that there are five clusters,
所以，如果看起来有五个集群，
um, for the word,
嗯，这个词，
the example I meant to use here is jaguar.
我打算在这里使用的例子是美洲虎。
Five clusters for the word jaguar,
捷豹这个词有五个星团，
I will just call them jaguar_1, jaguar_2, jaguar_3, four,
我会称他们为jaguar_1，jaguar_2，jaguar_3，四，
five, so it's just literally changed
五，所以它只是字面上改变了
the word in our corpus according to its cluster number.
我们语料库中的单词根据其簇号。
And then we run our word vectoring algorithm and so we get
然后我们运行我们的单词矢量算法，所以我们得到
a representation that each of those sensors of the word.
表示每个传感器的单词。
And basically, that works,
基本上，这是有效的，
right up the top is jaguar_1 next,
接下来是jaguar_1，
uh, luxury and convertible.
呃，豪华和敞篷车。
Um, here is, I guess there's a very old version of MacOS called Jaguar,
嗯，这里是，我猜有一个非常古老的MacOS版本叫Jaguar，
any remem- remember that one?
任何记忆 - 还记得吗？
Um. Right. So, jaguars right next to software and Microsoft up there, so that's hopeful.
嗯。对。因此，美洲虎紧挨着软件和微软那边，所以这是有希望的。
Um, here's the jaguar that's right next to the Hunter, um,
嗯，这是猎人旁边的美洲虎，嗯，
and I'm being confused on this one,
我对此感到困惑，
is jaguar as near solo musical keyboard and string.
是美洲虎作为近独奏音乐键盘和字符串。
Is there a band, [NOISE] a brand of keyboard called jaguar?
是否有乐队，[NOISE]一个名为美洲虎的键盘品牌？
I'm not quite sure about that one,
我不太确定那一个，
but anyway, it's sort of basically works.
但无论如何，它基本上是有效的。
Um, but that was sort of crude and it's also perhaps problematic,
嗯，但这有点粗糙，也可能有问题，
so a lot of time, the divisions between sensors aren't very clear, right?
所以很多时候，传感器之间的划分不是很明确，对吧？
A lot of sensors are actually related to each other and overlapping because
许多传感器实际上彼此相关并且重叠，因为
when how sensors normally arrive is that people stretch the meanings of words.
当传感器通常如何到达时，人们会延伸词语的含义。
It's not that they just sort of randomly
并不是他们只是随意的
wake up the next morning and say, "I know carpet.
第二天早上醒来说：“我知道地毯。
I could also refer to that as stone," um,
我也可以把它称为石头，​​“嗯，
and given a new sense to the word stone, right?
对石头这个词有了新的认识，对吧？
You so take something that you know about like
你这样拿一些你知道的东西
a web and you extend it metaphorically to other uses of webbing.
一个网络，你将其隐喻地扩展到其他网络使用。
Um, so here's a perhaps more interesting things,
嗯，所以这里可能是更有趣的事情，
so this is the other Sanjeev Arora,
所以这是另一个Sanjeev Arora，
um, paper that I was going to mention.
嗯，我要提到的论文。
So, that what happens if you don't,
那么，如果你不这样做会发生什么，
um, if you don't have more than one cents for each word?
嗯，如果每个单词的分数不超过1美分？
Well, effectively what you get is that
嗯，实际上你得到的就是那个
the word vector that you learn is what's referred to by
你学到的单词向量是指的
physicists and fancy people as a superposition
物理学家和花哨的人作为叠加
of the word vectors of the different sentence, different sensors.
不同句子的词向量，不同的传感器。
By supersitio- superposition just means a weighted average.
通过超叠加仅仅意味着加权平均。
Um, um, [LAUGHTER] so that effectively
嗯，嗯，[笑声]这样有效
my meaning of pike is sort of
我对派克的意思是那种
a weighted average of the vectors for the different sensors of pike,
派克不同传感器的矢量加权平均值，
and the components are just weighted by their frequency.
并且组件仅按其频率加权。
Um, so that part maybe is perhaps not too surprising,
嗯，这部分也许不是太令人惊讶，
but the part that's really surprising is well,
但真正令人惊讶的部分很好，
if we just averaging these word vectors,
如果我们只是平均这些单词向量，
you'd think you couldn't get anything out of the average, right|?
你认为你无法从平均水平中得到任何东西，对吧？
Like if I tell you I'm thinking of two numbers and they're here,
就像我告诉你我想到两个数字而他们在这里，
weighted sum is 54,
加权和是54，
what are my two numbers, right?
我的两个号码是什么，对吧？
You are sort of really short of information to be able to answer my question.
你有点缺乏能够回答我的问题的信息。
But, well, you know,
但是，嗯，你知道，
for these word vectors, um,
对于这些单词向量，嗯，
we have these high dimensional spaces and even though there
我们有这些高维空间，即使在那里
are a lot of words that the space is so vast for thoughts dimensions,
对于思想维度来说空间是如此巨大的很多话
that actual words or sensors are very sparse in that space.
在那个空间里，实际的单词或传感器非常稀疏。
And so it turns out that there's this whole literature on, um,
所以事实证明，这整篇文献都是关于的，嗯，
sparse coding, compressed sensing,
稀疏编码，压缩感知，
um, some of which has actually done by people in the stats department here,
嗯，其中一些实际上是由统计部门的人员在这里完成的，
um, which shows that in these cases where you have these sort of sparse,
嗯，这表明在这些情况下你有这种稀疏，
um, codes in these high dimensional spaces,
嗯，这些高维空间的代码，
you can actually commonly reconstruct out the components of a superposition,
你实际上可以通常重建叠加的组件，
even though all you've done is sort of done this weighted average,
即使你所做的一切都是按照加权平均值完成的，
and so, um, this paper looks at how you can do this and so they have,
所以，嗯，这篇论文着眼于你如何做到这一点，所以他们有，
um, these underlying meaning components,
嗯，这些潜在的意义成分，
and they sort of separated out.
他们有点分开了。
So, tie has one meaning component,
所以，领带有一个含义组成部分，
there's in this space of trousers, blouse, waistcoat,
这里有裤子，衬衫，背心，
that makes sense, and other one in this meaning component of seasoned teams,
这是有道理的，而另一个在经验丰富的团队的意义组成部分，
winning league, makes sense.
赢得联赛，有道理。
Um, scoreline goal with equalizer clinching scorers,
嗯，得分平衡器得分手的得分线，
this one seems to overlap with this one a bit.
这个似乎与这个有点重叠。
Um, but here tie,
嗯，但这里领带，
this is sort of cable ties and wire ties and things like that.
这是一种电缆扎带和电线扎带等类似的东西。
So, they are actually able to pull out the different sense meanings,
所以，他们实际上能够理解不同的意义，
um, from outside, out of the meaning of the word.
嗯，从外面看，出于这个词的意思。
Um, so that is a kind of a cool thing.
嗯，这是一件很酷的事情。
I just wanna, um,
我只想，嗯，
say one more thing.
再说一件事。
Okay. [NOISE] All the evaluations so far was intrinsic,
好的。 [NOISE]迄今为止的所有评估都是内在的，
um, you also might wanna do extrinsic evaluation.
嗯，你也可能想做外在的评价。
Why, why word vectors excited people on NLP so much?
为什么，为什么单词向量激动人们对NLP这么多？
Is it turned out that having this meaning,
事实证明有这个含义，
having this representation meaning just turned out to be
具有这种表达意义只是证明了
very useful and sort of improve all of your tasks after that.
非常有用，并在此之后完善所有任务。
Um, and so, um,
嗯，等等，嗯，
this is doing named entity recognition which is labeling
这是做标记的命名实体识别
persons and locations and organizations, but, you know,
人员，地点和组织，但是，你知道，
it's typical of many tasks of what people found,
它是人们发现的许多任务的典型代表，
was if you started with a model without sort of word representations
如果你开始使用没有单词表示的模型
and you throw in your word vectors regardless of whether they were to vehicle GloVe ones,
然后你把你的单词向量扔进去，不管它们是否属于车辆GloVe，
just kind of your numbers go up a couple of percent or more?
只是你的数字上涨百分之几或更多？
And so word vectors were just sort of this useful source that you could
因此，单词向量只是这种有用的来源
throw into any NLP system that you build and your numbers went up.
扔进你建立的任何NLP系统，你的数字上升了。
So, that there was just a very effective technology, um,
那么，只有一种非常有效的技术，嗯，
which actually did work in
实际上确实有效
basically any extrinsic tasks you type tried it on. Okay. Thanks a lot.
基本上你输入的任何外在任务都试过了。好的。非常感谢。